-=THE LAST FANTASY=-  荣誉出品  本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-  翻译：白浅  校对：拉拉叫我爆爆
灰姑娘的故事：曾经的歌
淡定点，因为姐要全力出击了
[SINGING] Hold on `cause I`m letting go
我会俘获你的心，就像牛仔套住斗牛
I`m gonna lasso your heart like a rodeo
我只会给你一些爱，除非你想要更多
I`m gonna give you some Till you want some more
因为我看到了一扇敞开的门
`Cause all I see is an open door
我看到它在指引我，它所有的能量
And I see where it`s leading me All of this energy
都被压抑了太久，它很强大，很强大
Been bottled up way too long It`s powerful, powerful
你懂我的意思吧，我已经整装待发
You see what I`m getting at I`m ready for all of that
说我不是明星，是你没眼光
If I`m not a star, you`re blind
我手戴漂亮戒指，我头发闪闪发亮
I`ve got rings on my fingers And glitter in my hair
我手拿单程票，刚刚抵达此处
I`ve got a one-way ticket And I just got here
我要跑遍这座城市，跑遍这座城市
I`m gonna run this town Run this town
我脚踩细高跟鞋，我踹开一扇扇心门
I`ve got high heel stilettos And I`m kicking in doors
我这么闪亮亮，可不是要讨好你
And kissing your ass Ain`t what my lipstick`s for
我要跑遍这座城市，跑遍这座城市
I`m gonna run this town Run this town
早饭呢? 我要吃鸡蛋饼和意大利面!
Where`s breakfast? I want waffles, spaghetti!
意大利面和鸡蛋饼!噢!噢!
Spaghetti waffles! Whoo. Whoo!
维克特，维克特,在房间里乖乖等着
Victor. Victor. PIease wait in the house, please.
[VICTOR GROANS]
我都闹饥荒了
My body is entering hunger shock.
[THUD]
噢，糟了，猫在书房里便便了
Oh, bad news. The cat pooped in the den.
更糟的是，我用你的毛毯擦便便了
Worse news, I used your blanket to clean it up.
- 我们又没养猫  - 我可没骗你噢
-We don`t have a cat. -No kidding.
[DOOR SLAMS AND VICTOR LAUGHS]
[DOOR CREAKS]
噢，我…对不起，我以为你还在睡
Oh. I-- Sorry. I didn`t think you`d be awake.
您和盖伊·摩根…
You have an appointment...
…有个约会，您应该不想迟到吧
...with Guy Morgan, I didn`t think you`d wanna be Iate.
噢，你想的真周全，宝贝
Oh, Iook at you thinking. Cute.
但画肖像画的时间还是有的
But I always have time for my portrait.
画师，画得再像点
Look alive. Paint.
我有点头晕
I`m feeling spiritually blocked.
备好热水，我要洗芝麻浴
Draw me a sesame seed bath.
芝麻浴!快去准备
Bath. Now.
现在，把老娘我画得再漂亮点，再瘦点
Now, make momma Iook more beautiful and thinner.
[WATER RUNNING]
放水声音小点
And make that water more quiet.
- 贝芙，你起床了没?  - 当然
-Bev, you awake? -Of course I`m awake.
要是等你来才起，我早就迟到了
If I waited for you, I`d never be on time.
幸亏你从没等过我
Lucky you never wait for me then.
维克特，不要
KATIE: Victor, no.
额，您不用杯子盛着喝吗?
Uh, don`t you want a glass?
恩，泥土味，有点鱼腥味，  还有点可爱的沙子味
Hmm. Earthy. A tad fishy. Lovely gravel finish.
你又让维克特在果汁机里放虫子了?
Did you Iet Victor put worms in the blender again?
是的，我是说…不是我让他放的
Yes. I mean, no.
我是说，是他自己放的
I mean, it just happened.
想害死我，门都没有
You know nothing can kill me.
绝对不可能
Nothing.
踩油门，凯蒂，这个约会我可不能迟到
GAIL: Step on it, Katie. I cannot be Iate for this meeting.
必要的话，就从这些人身上开过去
Just run them over if you have to.
[STUDENTS SCREAMING]
[CELL PHONE RINGS AND GAIL SIGHS]
你好，不，学生们不需要什么图书馆
Hello? No, the kids don`t need a Iibrary.
我是校长，我说了算，我要改建办公室
I am the dean, and the dean gets what she wants, and I wanna remodel.
你太无聊了，我说的是实话，  我们没什么可谈的了
You`re just boring. I`m being honest. I don`t know what else to tell you.
而且要在我和盖伊·摩根会面之前搞定
GAIL: And I wanted my office done for my meeting with Guy Morgan...
…他是音乐界泰斗，可你把我的话当耳边风
...the music mogul, but no.
还把舞会的主题定为宝莱坞?
And using Bollywood as a theme for the dance?
一点美国味都没有，我才不管是不是我说的
That`s totally un-American. I don`t care if it was my idea.
你好啊
GUY: Hello. GAIL: Oh. Oh.
我是凡·莱文斯威校长，您是--
I`m Dean Van Ravensway, and you must be--
- 盖伊·摩根  - 没错，盖伊·摩根先生，见到你很高兴
-Guy Morgan. -Ah, yes. Guy Morgan, a pleasure.
您看起来就是见多识广的人
You Iook Iike a man who knows things.
哈哈，也许我知道的太多了
Aha, even some things I shouldn`t know.
- 我是鲁克  - 很好
-And I`m Luke. GAIL: Great.
[GAIL LAUGHS]
[GUY CHUCKLES]
[GAIL CLEARS THROAT]
盖伊，您真的是美国偶像的新评委吗?
So tell me, Guy, is it true? Are you the new judge on Idol?
只能说兰迪（美偶评委）不受待见了
Well, Iet`s just say that Randy may be in the doghouse.
- 现在，来说说我儿子吧  - 好啊
-Now, Iet`s talk about my son. -Of course.
- 看过你的课程表没，鲁克?  - 恩，看过了
-Have you reviewed your schedule, Luke? -Yes, I have.
其实我想加一节音乐课，音乐理论课…
In fact, um, I`d Iike to add a music class. Um, the music theory--
威尔斯利学院有个很棒的商务课程，  我们就是冲着这个来的
Wellesley has a great business program. That`s why we`re here.
音乐界只有两种人：艺术家和生意人
There are two types of people in the music biz: artists and businessmen.
- 鲁克是当生意人的料  - 当然
-Luke is a businessman. -Of course.
凯蒂!过来，精神点，给你点事儿做
Katie, get in here. Look alive. Make yourself useful.
鲁克需要熟悉下校园的环境
Luke is gonna need a tour of the campus.
给贝芙发条短信，让她陪鲁克逛逛
So text Bev and ask her to escort Mr. Morgan around campus.
鲁克，要是你有令尊一半的制作人潜质…
Now, Luke, if you are half as talented a producer as your father--
现在下结论还早，他还差得远
The verdict`s still out. He hasn`t earned it.
听过我在音乐界的奋斗史吗?
Heard the story of how I started in the music business?
- 听过，爸爸，每个人都听过  - 那每个人都该知道故事的发展了
-Yes, everybody`s heard it, Dad. -Then everybody should know how it goes.
那时我还在为滚石乐队工作…
There I was, working for The Rolling Stones...
- …当时米克他…  - 爸
-...when Mick himself-- -Dad.
好，不说了，重点是我儿子还不成器
Fine. As I said, the verdict is still out on my son.
他才只出了一张专辑，叫果味危机乐队?
He just produced an album with the Fruity Dangers?
您说的是危险水果乐队吧?
Do you mean Danger Fruit?
那张唱片很棒的
That record was amazing.
我记不得了，因为我一个子儿都没赚到
I forgot what they were called because they made me absolutely no money.
[CHUCKLES]
谢谢你，难得能遇到听过他们专辑的人
Thank you. Rare I meet anyone who`s heard their album.
你说笑吧?那支乐队红极一时的
What, are you kidding? They`re a cult phenomenon.
不好意思，你们俩怎么说上了?
I`m sorry. Why are you talking?
我想要鲁克学会如何发掘有商业价值的新星
GUY: What I need is for Luke to Iearn to spot a commercially viable star.
形象不要太差，明白吗?
Image drives the bottom Iine, right?
我明白，要是贾斯汀·比伯又丑又矮，  能有比伯热潮嘛?
I feel you. Would we have Bieber Fever if he were an ugly troll?
说实话，他是有点矮，对吧?
Actually, he is a tad hobbit-Iike, isn`t he?
我希望能由鲁克监制贵校的学期汇演…
I`d Iike Luke to produce your Semester Showcase...
- …看看他能不能发掘出受欢迎的新人  - 学期汇演一向是我来筹办的
-...to see if he can identify sellable talent. -I produce the Semester Showcase.
我会出双倍的汇演预算经费
I will double your Showcase budget.
也会邀请所有我认识的星探
I will invite every talent scout I know.
这将是我们相互合作的开始…
This could be the beginning of a relationship...
…韦尔斯利学院和肯星顿唱片公司合作
...between Wellesley and Kensington Records.
我们学校似乎要迎来一位新的制作人了
Looks Iike we have a new producer.
对了，这是我的女儿，贝芙
Oh, and this is my daughter, Bev.
贝芙，这位是白金畅销家，格莱美获得者…
Bev, this is the platinum-selling, Grammy-winning...
…以及英俊潇洒的制作人，盖伊·摩根
...and very handsome producer, Guy Morgan.
你能带他的儿子鲁克观赏下校园吗?
Could you give his son, Luke, a tour?
当然,你想参观威尔斯利学院吗?
Sure. Would you Iike to see the Wellesley perks?
额，好啊，很期待，我很乐意
Um, yes, brilliant. Sure.
- 凯蒂  - 我喜欢你的口音
-Katie. BEV: I Iove your accent.
- 凯蒂  - 今晚来我家玩吗
GAIL: Katie. BEV: Wanna come over tonight?
你还傻愣在这儿干嘛?出去
What are you still doing here? Go.
我和盖伊有要事商谈，你出去，马上!
Guy and I have things we need to discuss. Out. Now.
盖伊，能不能讲讲，  您那时在米克手下工作的感觉呢?
So, Guy, you`ve gotta tell me, what was that Iike working under Mick?
小心!
Watch out.
- 这球真危险  - 哈，是啊，谢啦
-Dangerous balls. -Ha, ha. Thanks.
- 你有鼓起勇气把唱片交给他吗?  - 喂!
-So you womanned up and did it? BOY 1 : Hey!
- 算给了  - 喂!
-Oh, I did it. BOY 1 : Hey!
- 究竟怎样?  - 能把球还给我们吗?
-What happened? BOY 2: Can we have our ball?
可我没能把我的的CD给鲁克
I didn`t give my CD to Luke.
我把它偷偷塞进他爸的包里了
I snuck it in his dad`s bag.
但至少盖伊·摩根有你的录音带了呀，  很了不起了，你只要得到赏识
But Guy Morgan has your demo. That`s huge. What you need is a champion.
不，我只要能够顺利毕业
No, what I need is to graduate.
把球还给我们，给不给?
You giving our ball back or what?
噢，你想要这个吗?
Oh, do you want this?
她一射门就进球了，厉害吧，足球小子
She shoots, she scores. Unlike you, soccer boy.
[CHUCKLES]
赶紧说说，鲁克·摩根真有传说中那么帅吗?
Oh, so spill it. Is Luke Morgan as hot as everyone Tweets he is?
真人比传说中更帅
Hotter.
你该请他参加舞会
You should ask him to the dance.
可我在男生面前总是表现得太笨了
Because I`m so forward with guys.
万事开头难嘛
First time for everything, right?
- 嗨，鲁克  - 你好
-Hi, Luke. -Hello.
听听我的录音CD吧
You have to hear my demo.
这可是复古摇滚爵士乐的大融合
It`s a retro-funk-jazz explosion.
都往后退点!我才是第一个
Back off. I was here first.
淡定，别激动，放松点  我哥们暂时不想要你们的试音唱片
Hold on, hold up. PIease hold on. My boy does not want your demos yet.
靠边，往前走，再见
Walk away. Move along. Bye.
不管怎样，和你聊天很开心
It was nice chatting or whatever that was.
- 你好，我是…  - 鲁克·摩根，对吧?
-Yes, hi, I`m, uh-- -Luke Morgan, right?
学期汇演的制作人
Who is producing the Showcase.
我还不一定会做，所以得低调些
I don`t think I`m gonna do the Showcase, so I need to keep a Iow profile--
恩，我懂，听好了，这学校里有两种人
Yeah, yeah. Listen close now. There`s two kinds of people in this school.
一些人跟风，一些人引领潮流
There are the wannabes and there`s gonnabes.
你和我，属于引领潮流的人,  那我们做什么呢? 离那些跟风的人远点
You and I, we`re gonnabes. What do we do? We stay away from the wannabes, all right?
还有叫尤兰达的女生远点，尤其有三个很疯的
And girls named Yolanda. There are three of them and they are certifiably--
很疯?你竟然会吸引能疯的女孩?震惊啊
Crazy? You attract crazy women? Shocking.
虽然我看起来不怎么吸引女孩子，  但女士们都需要一个倾听者
It may seem Iike I don`t have game, but Iadies Iove a Iistener.
还有，我跟你说，让我帮你找点节目吧
PIus, I`m telling you, Iet me help you find acts.
- 啊，那你是星探咯?  - 额，其实我是个DJ
-Ah, so you`re a talent scout? -Well, bottom Iine, I`m a DJ.
- 噢，你还个是DJ?  - 看我给你露一手
-Oh, you`re a DJ as well? -Check this.
[BEATBOXING]
[LUKE BEATBOXING]
哇
MICKEY: Whoa.
很好，我可能是需要你的帮助，  能遇见你太好了
Okay, yes. You could be very useful. It was nice meeting you.
你有舞伴了吗?我能帮你勾搭个
You got a girl for the dance? Because I can hook you up.
还没呢，谢谢
Uh, no. Thanks.
不过，你了解贝芙·凡·莱温斯莉吗?
Uh, but what do you know about Bev Van Ravensway?
- 今晚和她有约  - 贝芙?
-Supposed to see her tonight. -Bev?
- 是啊  - 她很性感…
-Yeah. -She`s hot...
…但她是个疯子，也很能惹事儿
... but the girl is mad, mad drama, okay?
我跟你聊了这么久，你还不知道我是谁吧
I am talking to you and you don`t even know my name.
- 我是米克·欧马利  - 米克·欧马利
-I`m Mickey O`Malley. -Mickey O`Malley.
爱尔兰小区里的独行侠
A rarity in the Irish community.
嗷姆
GAIL: Om.
- 噢姆  - 嗷姆
RAVI: Om. -Om.
- 噢姆  - 嗷姆!
-Om. -Om!
格尔夫人，这不是在比赛
This is not a contest, Ms. Gail.
专注于你的呼吸即可
Just concentrate on your breathing.
我的屁股坐僵了
My butt is numb.
你的屁股在受苦，就是你整个人都在受苦
If your butt is suffering, then you are suffering.
实际上，你整个生活都在受苦，为什么呢?
In fact, your entire Iife is suffering. Why?
因为你渴望之物皆为虚妄
Because you crave that which is meaningless.
你是在说我肤浅?
Are you calling me shallow?
没这个意思，我是想让你停止无谓的渴望，  让你的臀部得到放松
No, I`m saying to stop your craving and release your butt.
放松点，再放松点，放松你的臀部
Just release it. Release it, yeah. Release that butt.
放松你的臀部，很好，放松你的臀部
[SINGING] Release that butt Oh, yeah, release that butt
很好，放松你的臀部
Oh, yeah, release that butt
凡·莱文斯威夫人?
Mrs. Van Ravensway?
你这蹄子，敢在我冥想的时候捣乱
What part of ``if you interrupt my meditation...
扒了你的皮，你是哪里没听懂?
... I will jerk your tail in a knot`` do you not understand?
你不是说，晚饭好了告诉你一声
You told me to tell you when dinner was ready.
噢，谢天谢地，我现在特别想吃饭
Oh, thank God. I`m craving some bourbon.
维克特
KATIE: Victor.
- 晚饭好了  - 说点我不知道的事儿吧
-Oh. Um, dinner`s ready. -Tell me something I don`t know.
你知道掌管整个学院事务的压力有多大吗?
Do you have any idea how stressful it is to run this academy?
不错，我用那些钱去泡温泉了
Yes, I spent the money at the spa.
一晚五千美刀不算很贵…
Five thousand dollars a night is not very expensive...
…不然我就要精神崩溃了
...when you think about the alternative, which is me having a nervous breakdown.
Ow.
你在作甚?我在打电话
GAIL: What are you doing? I`m on the phone.
我在打扫卫生
-I`m cleansing. VICTOR: Heh, heh.
干酪通心粉
Mac and cheese.
我不需要你的精神安慰
GAIL: I don`t need your spiritual counseling.
我在考虑要不要让你卷铺盖伊走人
I`m thinking of firing you.
慢点喝，格尔夫人，  这样才能体会到万物为一的感觉
Pace yourself, Ms. Gail, or you will not be one with everything.
亲爱的，这样雇你才雇对了，  现在，让我和万物为一体吧
Honey, that`s what I got you for. Now, make me one with everything.
这个汇演真是让我郁闷
This Showcase is giving me the vapors.
我为什么要管这事?
How did this become my Iife?
我给你们讲过我差点飞黄腾达的事么?
Did I ever tell you all about the time I nearly got my big break?
- 讲过了  - 很好
ALL: Yes. -Good.
你们都该知道具体是怎么回事
Then you all know how it goes.
我不会屈服，我就要跳脱
[SINGING] I ain`t gonna leap, I`m gonna jump
找到我的方向，离开这鬼地方
Find my way right out of this dump
[CROWD SHOUTING AND BOOING]
- 我有音乐天赋，可他们让我成了--  - 笑柄
-I had talent, and they made me-- ALL: A Iaughingstock.
看看我现在
Now Iook at me.
我有两个不懂感恩的孩子…
I got two ungrateful kids...
…一个发育不良，头发乱糟糟，调皮捣蛋的仆人…
...a dwarfish, hairy, elfin servant...
一个穿着随便邋遢的亚洲古鲁（印度教精神导师）
...and a random tablecloth-wearing Asian--
- 是印度古鲁  - 天天说些废话
-Indian. --who makes no sense at all, ever.
妈妈，再喝一杯吧
Why don`t you have another drink, Mom.
[MIMICS BEV MOCKINGLY]
凯蒂，给我擦嘴巴
Katie, napkin me.
我不得不讨好盖伊·摩根…
I have got to impress Guy Morgan...
…这样我就不用假装喜欢这所讨厌的学校了…
...so I can stop pretending to care about this insufferable school...
…这样我们就能搬到好莱坞去了，  在那里谁都不用装
...and we can all move to Hollywood where no one pretends to care about anything.
妈，你把最重要的人给忘了，本小姐我呀
Mom, I think that you`re forgetting about the most important thing. Me.
盖伊一听到我的歌，就会跟我签约
Guy will give me a deal as soon as he hears me sing.
- 我不信  - 一定会的，人家真有很努力在练
-I doubt that. -No, I`ve been practicing really hard.
我的声乐老师说，  我的唱功已经达到了一种全新的高度
My voice teacher says I`ve transcended to a whole new Ievel.
不错，可是我还是不信
Yeah, I doubt it.
等我赚了第一笔钱，就给您老人家买豪宅…
When my first single drops, I`II buy you that mansion...
…住在好莱坞山庄里…
...in the Hollywood Hills...
这样你就有钱去拉长你的大腿了
...and you can finally afford to have your Iegs Iengthened.
- 噢，宝…  - 格尔夫人
-Oh, ba-- -Ms. Gail.
－贝芙小姐很有头脑  - 凯蒂
-Miss Bev has clarity. VICTOR: Katie.
- 你想想--  - 看
-You see-- -Look.
身份卑微的农民们在田地里耕作了40年，  期间一滴雨也没下
--the Iowly peasant tills the soil for 40 years without any rain.
但是最近发明了水耕法的无业商人…
But the unemployed salesman who has recently discovered hydroponics...
- …突然之间遭到嫌弃…  - 看到没?又是废话
-...all of a sudden gets disgusted by the-- -And see? No sense.
- 这些话很没意思  - 让我说完，您…
-That didn`t make any sense. -Let me finish. You--
我不信，你让我天天祈祷来着
Oh, I doubt it. You have me pray all day.
- 我又不是无知无觉的人  - 可你没心
-I don`t feel nothing. -You don`t have a soul.
- 你才没心  - 我有很多心，可以给你一颗
GAIL: No, you don`t have soul. -I have a many souls. I`II give you one.
- 你的第三只眼开了吗?  - 我还有第四只眼，想看吗?
-Where`s your third eye? Turn that thing on. -I have a fourth eye too. You wanna see it?
- 什么?  - 闭嘴
-What? -Shh.
我想要6尺4英寸的个子（1米93），  给我个惊喜吧，贝芙
I wanna be 6`4``. Wow me, Bev.
[PIANO NOTE PLAYS]
哆-来-咪-发-嗦-拉-西-哆
[SINGING OFF KEY] Do-re-mi-fa-so-la-ti-do
停，别嚎了，好吗?
Just stop. Stop the wowing, okay?
- 怎么了?  - 你水平下降了
BEV: What`s wrong? -Somehow you`ve gotten worse.
我不知道你竟然能唱成那样…
I don`t know how that was possible...
但就是高音修正器也修不了你的音
... but there isn`t enough Auto-Tune that`s gonna fix you.
- 是凯蒂钢琴弹得不好，影响我发挥  - 我觉得不是
-Well, Katie`s bad playing threw me off. -I don`t think it was that.
再来一次
Again.
不是吧? 好吧
Really? Okay.
哆-来-咪-发-嗦-拉-西-哆
[OFF KEY] Do-re-mi-fa-so-la-ti-do
嗷
Ouch.
我哼都比她唱得好
[WHISPERS] I could belch the song better.
[BURPS]
你又喝擦地板的蜡了?
Have you been drinking the floor wax again?
只要能忘记我住这个鬼地方，喝什么都成
Anything to forget I Iive here.
啊，我头疼，就像是蚊子吸了不新鲜的血
Ugh. My head is buzzing Iike a skeeter on a septic tank.
- 拉维，我要打坐冥想  －哥们，祝你好运
-Ravi, meditate me. [WHISPERS] Good Iuck, buddy.
哼，没关系，我自有计划
Well, it doesn`t matter, because I have my own plan.
我还蛮享受刚才那一幕的，是不是很坏?
Does it make me a bad person that I kind of enjoyed that?
不是
[BELCHES] No.
恩，哼的不错
Hmm. Nice work.
- 接下来我会干什么，猜猜看哦  - 现在别闹，维克特，我很忙
-Guess who`s on his way over. -Not now, Victor, I`m busy.
猜吗，不然等着被喷吧
Guess or prepare to get creamed.
[LAUGHING]
维克特!维克特!维克特，住手!
KATIE: Victor! Victor! Victor, stop!
[SHOWER RUNNING]
我手戴漂亮戒指
KATIE [SINGING]: I`ve got rings on my fingers
我头发闪闪发亮
And glitter in my hair
我手拿单程车票，刚刚抵达此处
I`ve got a one-way ticket And I just got here
我要跑遍…
I`m gonna run--
维克特，你在干嘛?
-Ha-ha-ha. -Victor, what are you doing?
维克特!
Victor!
维克特，你把我衣服放哪儿了?
Victor, where did you put my clothes?
- 惊喜吧!  - 什么?哦不!
-Surprise! -What? No.
[KATIE SHRIEKS]
我要杀了你，维克特!
KATIE: I`m gonna kill you. Victor!
[VICTOR LAUGHS]
[GRUMBLES]
你好啊，凯蒂
Oh, hi, Katie.
你这个恶魔，让我进来
You are evil. Let me in.
这座房子里的每一把锁都归我管
I control every Iock on this property.
该死
Crap.
真是疯了
This is insane.
对，试试小茅屋吧，门没锁，白痴
Yeah, try the shed, it`s unlocked, idiot.
[SIGHS]
你肯定是在开玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
[GASPS]
可恶
Crap.
我怎么生了这么个没内涵的女儿?
How did such an untalented daughter spring from my Ioins?
注意力集中，格尔夫人，  我们正在试着与你的内在神对话
Focus, Ms. Gail. We are making an offering to your personal deity.
告诉他，我要名，也要钱
Tell him to give me fame and fortune.
不是这么做的
Not exactly how it works.
现在，与你的穆拉神一同呼吸
Now, breathe through your Mula Bandha.
噢，亲爱的，要是我能做到的话，  我的视频点击量就要破百万了
Oh, honey, if I could do that, I`d get a million hits on YouTube.
这得多久?
How much Ionger is this gonna take? Ugh.
你说祈祷，还是说名和利?
The prayer or the fame and fortune?
待会儿见
Ha, ha. See you Iater.
维克特
Victor.
凯蒂?
LUKE: Katie?
- 鲁克  - 凯蒂
-Luke. -Katie.
- 你把地毯穿身上了?  - 是啊
-Are you wearing a doormat? -Yes.
- 欢迎来我家  - 谢谢
-Welcome. -Why, thank you.
其实，额…
The truth. Um....
我的继弟把我锁门外了
My stepbrother Iocked me outside of the house.
我什么都没穿
Naked.
哦，对不起，你应该--你应该穿上我的外套
Oh, sorry. You should-- You should take my jacket.
别客气
KATIE: Oh. -Oh, no, no.
穿上吧
There.
- 谢谢，还有裤子  - 啊?
-Thanks. Now the pants. -Hmm?
我开玩笑呢
I`m kidding.
我当真了
-You got me. -Ha, ha.
不，别吃
No, no.
再开一次家长会，我发誓我能瘦下来
One more parent-teacher conference, I swear I`m gonna Iose it.
看看我，我是搞教育的
Look at me. I`m an educator.
我没有真才实学，在我回到老爸的农场之前  我就会死翘翘的
I have no real skills. And I will die before I go back to my daddy`s farm.
告诉我的内在神，帮我得到盖伊·摩根，快
You tell my personal deity to help me achieve Guy Morgan. Do it.
那我再在这个圣餐台上放一只香蕉
I`II put another banana on the altar.
[ANGELIC CHOIR SINGING NEARBY]
那是什么?
What is that?
你听到天使的歌声了吗?
Do you hear angels singing?
可能是上天对你祈祷的回应吧
Perhaps the gods have answered your prayer.
嘿，你--?
Hey. What--?
[DOORBELL RINGS]
[ANGELIC CHOIR SINGING ON CELL PHONE]
- 我是格尔·凡·莱文斯威  - 你好
-This is Gail Van Ravensway. GUY [ON PHONE]: Hello.
我是盖伊·摩根，你还好吗?
Guy Morgan here. How are you?
啊，好啊，盖伊伊
Oh, well, hello, Guy.
你会打这个电话真让人吃惊啊
What a surprise to see you calling this number.
听到这首音乐了吗?
Do you hear this?
[KATIE SINGING ON STEREO] I can justify
这是你女儿凯蒂的录音带…
That`s the demo your girl, Katie...
掉进了我的公文包里
...slipped into my briefcase.
我感觉她能红，亲爱的
And it sounds Iike money, dear.
她给了你张CD?
She gave you a CD?
那真是太妙了
Oh, well. Well, ain`t that the berries.
拉维，你祈祷的是什么牛鬼蛇神?
Ravi, what frigging god did you pray to?
嗯，盖伊伊，貌似有人在说谎
Guy, yeah, it seems someone`s not being entirely honest here.
[DOORBELL RINGING]
凯蒂，快去开门!
Katie, somebody get that door!
那么…
So...
…今天的碰面…
...that meeting today...
…很显然是你爸爸不理解你
...it was obvious that your dad doesn`t get you.
他不喜欢你的音乐是他的损失
He`s an idiot for not Iiking your music.
额，这个…这个很复杂
Well, it`s-- It`s complicated.
我还是…
I`m gonna just, uh....
[DOORBELL RINGS]
比我的状况还复杂么?
Is it as complicated as me...
被锁在家门外，只有一条地毯可以裹身?
...getting stuck outside in only a welcome mat?
这不复杂啊,这是上帝的恩赐
That`s not complicated. That is a gift from God.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
[DOOR OPENS]
鲁克，凯蒂，你们在干什么?
Luke. Katie. What are you doing?
呵呵，看来你弟弟是个迷你版小撒旦
Well, it seems your brother is Satan`s very own personal Mini-Me.
可不是嘛，快进来吧
Oh, I know, tell me about it. Come on in.
天哪，你今天很累吧?
Oh, my God, did you work out today?
- 坐吧  - 看看这个
-Sit down. -Ooh, Iook at this.
- 喝柠檬汁  - 谢谢
-Ha, ha. Some Iemonade. -Why, thank you.
我妹妹凯蒂，她身体有点问题…
You know, my stepsister, she has body issues...
她有暴露癖，我不想扫她的兴
...so I don`t Iike to discourage her nudity.
有意思
That`s interesting.
- 她非常可爱--  - 要不要吃点点心?
-She`s absolutely Iovely-- -Would you Iike an appetizer?
水果奶酪
Oh, fromage.
我只有纯奶酪
I only have cheese.
我刚刚和盖伊·摩根通了电话
I just got off the phone with Guy Morgan.
你的电话
Your phone.
他爱死你的那张录音CD了
He just Ioved that Iittle demo you Ieft him.
是我小看了你
I have underestimated you.
要是我在乎你，我会为你骄傲的
It`d make me proud if I cared about you.
- 我没撒谎  - 不，小妞，你说谎了
-I didn`t Iie about anything. -Oh, but, chicken, you did.
至少在我解释之后，盖伊认为你是在说谎
At Ieast that`s what Guy thinks, now that I`ve clarified.
我告诉他那是贝芙的录音CD，是你偷来的
I told him it was Bev`s demo and that you stole it from her.
- 你不能这么做，那是我的歌  - 那是贝芙的歌
-But you can`t do that. That`s my song. -It`s Bev`s song.
盖伊很期待贝芙在学期汇演上的表现
And Guy can`t wait to see her perform it at the Showcase.
你要是胆敢联系盖伊，我就和你断绝一切关系，  把你锁在地下室里
If you try to contact him, I`II deny everything and Iock you in the basement.
- 她不能通过唱歌来拯救自己  - 她是不能，但是你可以，不是吗?
-She can`t sing to save her Iife. -No, but you can, can`t you?
现在，我要听听这美妙的歌声
Now, Iet`s hear this amazing voice.
[PLAYING GUITAR AND SINGING]
像是个恶性肿瘤，她一点幽默感也没有
Like a malignant tumor She`s got no sense of humor
像是个溃烂脓包，最好奋起反抗她
Just like a swollen blister It`s best to just resist her
她可算不上女巫，她只是个恶毒的贱…
She`s not exactly a witch She`s just a terrible bi--
歌词真垃圾
Well, your Iyrics stink.
但是盖伊说得对，你确实有点天赋
But Guy`s right, you`ve got chops.
[LUKE PLAYING PIANO]
[BEV SMASHES KEYS]
知道我还擅长什么乐器么?
Do you know what other instruments I`m good at?
我感觉要是回答这个问题的话，会有麻烦
I have a feeling I could get in trouble with a question Iike that.
我喜欢麻烦
I Iike trouble.
嘿，孩子们
GAIL: Hey, kids.
- 晚上好，凡·莱文斯威夫人  - 对不住了，我需要你出去，现在就走
-Good evening, Miss Van Ravensway. -Sorry, I need you to go. Now.
家庭紧急状况，我需要贝芙协助我排出肾结石
Family emergency. I need Bev to help me pass a kidney stone.
- 她度过了个愉快的夜晚，拜拜  - 您是想毁了我的人生吗?
-So she had a Iovely evening. Ta-ta. -Are you trying to ruin my Iife?
我想到了你在汇演上博得盖伊青睐的方法
I have figured out a way for you to wow Guy Morgan in the Showcase.
- 你觉得我唱功提高了?  - 哦，不是的，宝贝  363
-So you do think I`ve improved? -Oh, no, honey.
但是我的内在神告诉我…
But my month of spiritual devotion has taught me...
…上帝显灵的方式总是很烦人
...that God works in annoying ways.
要是我不能唱，怎么赢得盖伊的认可啊?
How am I to wow Guy Morgan if I supposedly can`t sing?
你不能唱，但是凯蒂可以
You can`t, but Katie can.
- 什么?  - 我知道你会吃惊，就像我说的，很烦人
-What? -I know. Like I said, annoying.
我们会录下她的声音，然后你假唱
We`II record her voice and you will Iip synch.
要是我不同意呢?
What if I don`t want to?
别跟我耍花招，你个不懂知恩图报的小蹄子
Don`t you get snarky with me, you ungrateful toad.
- 是我救了你  - 你什么都没做
-I saved your Iife. -You didn`t do anything.
- 是我爸爸娶了你  - 是啊，可他没多久就死了
-My dad married you. -Yeah, and then he died.
我本想把你寄养，可人家嫌你长得丑
I tried to put you in foster care, but they was all fulled up on ugly.
- 这话倒有趣  - 我觉得那是…
-Funny. -I thought it was...
…因为你不想别人指责你
...because you don`t wanna Iook bad.
凯蒂，要是你不唱…
Katie, if you don`t sing...
…我会想方设法花光你爸爸留下的那笔遗产
...I`m gonna find a way for that savings your dad Ieft to disappear.
也就是说，你会失学，不能在外面住，  只能拴在我身边
That means, you forget college, moving out, you`re stuck here with me.
不过，小鬼头，我们一起慢慢变老会很有趣的
But, pumpkin, we`re gonna have so much fun growing old together.
既然你这么喜欢她，干嘛不让她去表演?
Why don`t you just have her perform if you Iike her so much?
这是因为，宝贝，看看你自己
Because, honey, Iook at you.
你是明星的料
You are a star.
这正是盖伊要的，明星
That is what Guy Morgan needs. You, the star.
我是明星
I`m a star.
- 闪亮耀眼的明星  - 没错，就是这样
-A bright, gassy star. -Yes, you are.
盖伊·摩根先生会送你个游泳池…
And Guy Morgan is gonna give you a swimming pool...
…形状跟科林·法瑞尔（影星）一模一样
...shaped just Iike Colin Farrell.
他的每个棱角
Every part of him.
贝芙，你只要上网，  就能看到科林·法瑞尔的一举一动
Or, Bev, you could just see every part of Colin Farrell on the Internet.
这事我不想参与
And just Ieave me out of this.
- 那我们该怎么做?  - 撒谎准则一…
-Okay, so how do we do this? -First rule of Lie CIub...
…就是不要谈论撒谎这件事儿
...is don`t talk about Lie CIub.
你也不能说，凯蒂
Which includes you, Katie.
在其他人看来，你是不会唱歌的
As far as everyone knows, you can`t sing.
而且不准再跟鲁克或是盖伊搭话了
And no more talking to Luke or Guy.
明白了吗?
Are we clear?
完全明白
Crystal.
[BELL TOLLING]
是的，爸爸，我们就要去见一些新人了
Yeah, Dad, we`re about to meet some fresh talent right now.
还记得您签Jay-Z（说唱艺人）那会吗?  你没打算签他的，爸爸
Remember when you signed Jay-Z? No, you passed on him, my bad.
这跟那时很像，不过这次会很成功
Um, this is Iike that, except it`s gonna be brilliant.
恩，好吧
Yeah. Okay.
- 好的，拜  - 鲁克，他怎么说?
-Yeah, okay. Bye. -Dude, what`d he say?
你给我说过的那些人能行?
These guys you told me about are good?
不错，"口头多数"乐队很有潜力，  他们来随时会到
Yes. The Oral Majority has potential. They`II be here any second.
说起潜力，你跟贝芙的小约会感觉咋样?
Talking about potential, how was your Iittle date with Bev?
- 她妈妈把我踢出来了  - 我告诉过你，她是个麻烦妞
-Her mom kicked me out. -I told you. Bev is drama.
确切地说，是格尔夫人很麻烦
Technically, it was Gail`s drama.
不过贝芙很吸引人，哥们，她…
But Bev`s interesting, man. She`s--
我担心她是那种爱疯又傻气的女生
I`m worried she`s bonkers.
我的前女友，她很性感，但是很神经
See, my Iast girlfriend, she was hot, but absolutely mental.
我想要一个头脑正常点的女友
I need a girl who`s not gonna be shipped to the Ioony bin.
等会儿聊，我要如厕
Hang on, I`m gonna hit the facilities.
如-厕…新词嘛
Facilities. That`s a new one.
- 嘿，哥们，不好意思我们来晚了  - 嗨，你们都有什么好事儿没?
-Hey, man. Sorry we`re Iate. -Hey, what`s good, y`all?
等他上完厕所出来再说
Nobody talks to my boy until he comes from the facilities.
我们要让他印象深刻
We`re here to impress.
- 明白了吗?  - 明白了
-CIear, right? -Got it.
战斗的时候，就要保持清醒
[SINGING] When you`re fighting just to keep it sane
在暴风眼，放飞你的意志
Throw your will At the eye of the hurricane
- 大声唱  - 噢，噢，噢
-Sing it out -Eh-oh, eh-oh, eh-oh
- 和我大声唱  - 哦，哦，哦
-Help me sing it out -Eh-oh, eh-oh, eh-oh
想要知道自己是谁，停下奔跑的脚步
If you wanna find out who you are Stop running
最后你会发现，自己什么都不是
In the end you`ll figure out It`s all about nothing
- 整晚，这会是一整个夜晚  - 嘿，嘿，嘿
All night, it`s gonna be all right Hey, hey, hey, hey
整个夜晚，把你的梦带入现实
All right Turn your dreams into your life
很不错
That`s good.
搞定了，没人跟踪我，我收到你消息了
I`m clean. No one followed me. And I got your intel.
亲爱的凯蒂，你的生活真是一团糟
Oh, Katie, baby, your Iife sucks.
信不，现在更糟了
Trust me, it gets worse.
大哥，那些人，他们竟然在那种地方开唱…
Okay, dude, those guys, they just went Oral Majority on me in there--
- 我不是没拦他们  - 你说的对
-I was trying to hold them back-- -You`re right.
他们很有才
They have potential and they`re great.
但是，我的星探朋友，我得说一点，  你得保证我以后别在盥洗室搞试唱了
But first, my talent-finding friend, promise me no more auditions in the bogs.
- 那什么?  - 卫生间啊
-The what? -The Ioo.
- 洗手间，厕所  - 明白了
-Bathroom. Toilet. -Got it.
那就好，来，我要给你看点东西
AII right. Okay, come on. I wanna show you something.
所以现在，我得偷偷排练了
So now I have to rehearse in secret.
不排练又咋了?
Why not not rehearse?
让贝芙当众出丑呗，你怕什么?
Make Bev sound bad. What do you care?
不唱的话，就不给我钱，我怎么活
No song, no savings account. No Iife.
[CHATTERING AND LAUGHING]
有人来了，快躲起来
ANGELA: People. Coming. Now.
好了
Okay.
老大，我们来干嘛?别吊我胃口了
Dude, what are we doing? The suspense is killing me.
帮我把麦克风架好行吗?
LUKE: Can you grab the mike?
你该不会要向某男表白吧?
Not about to serenade a brother, are you?
老兄，讲基情，我会翻脸的
LUKE: Dude, with bromance, comes a fine Iine.
好，我不说了
MICKEY: That I shall not cross.
那唱点什么吧
So sing something.
成
LUKE: Okay.
[PLAYING UPBEAT MELODY]
我迷失在这个世界，它让我头脑发懵
[SINGING] I`m lost in a world That rattles my brain
我要打扫自己的生活，清除你制造的混乱
I`m cleaning up my life From the mess you made
噢，噢
Oh, oh
喔，噢，噢
Whoa, oh, oh, oh
我的灵魂还在内疚，但我已不欠你什么
My soul`s in debt, but my bills are paid
我愿意倾尽所有，只为从中逃脱
I`d give anything just to make an escape
噢，噢
Oh, oh
喔,噢，噢，噢
Whoa, oh, oh, oh
你可以继续敲门，敲门，敲门
So you can keep Knocking, knocking, knocking
宝贝，你很棒，但我再不会让你走进我心
Baby, you`re rockin` But there ain`t no way I`m ever letting you in
他唱的真好
[MOUTHS] He`s amazing.
不会再让你进来
Not again
继续敲吧，敲吧，敲吧
So keep on Knocking, knocking, knocking
但是宝贝，你最好知趣的走开，  因为我不会再让你走进我心
But, baby, you`re better off walking `Cause I ain`t gonna let you in
绝不会再让你进来
Never again
我再次身陷泥泞
I went out on a limb again
我想我只能以退为进
I guess I had to lose to win
我太迷茫，不知道何去何从
I was too confused to know Which way to turn
[CELL PHONE BEEPS]
- 她可能是个百万富翁…  - 该死
-And she could be a millionaire.... -Crap.
- 格尔让我开车送她回家  - 我不看重这个
-Gail needs me to drive her home. -I don`t care
因为，亲爱的，家里没人
`Cause, baby, there`s nobody home
没人在家，哈
Nobody`s home at all, yeah
[MICKEY LAUGHS]
- 什么?词是你自己写的?  - 是
-What? Did you write that? -Yeah.
这让我想起了……额
Reminds me of, um.... Uh....
- 危险水果，对吧?危险水果乐队  - 我也为他们的专辑作词了
-Danger Fruit, right? Danger Fruit. -Ha, ha. Because I wrote their album too.
不是吧，我还一直在网上找盗版
Shut up. Took me forever to find that bootleg online.
- 我爱死那张专辑了，它太棒了  - 嗯
-I Iove that album. That`s crazy. -Yeah.
这事儿我爸不知道，他觉得那张专辑…
My dad doesn`t know. And he thought the record...
…就是一泡屎
...was a pile of crap.
他觉得写歌很浪费时间
He thinks writing`s a waste of time.
他只希望我像他那样，但我发型帅点
Because he basically wants me to be Iike him. Only with better hair.
但是当我听到那些男生在厕所唱歌的  第一个想法是…
But the first thing I thought when I heard those guys in the urinals was...
…房间音效不错
...good acoustics.
第二个想法是，这些人，这些人会很了不起
Second thought was these guys, these guys could be great.
要是你肯为他们写歌的话
If you gave them your song.
哥们，这个主意真不错
Mate, that`s a brilliant idea.
- 那他们能去汇演上演出吗  - 能
-So put them in the Showcase? -Put them in the Showcase.
太好了
MICKEY: Yeah.
[KATIE PLAYING GUITAR AND SINGING]
你不知道会发生什么
You can never tell where this might go
这是你今天写的歌?
You wrote that song today?
- 你才在家里待了多久，两个小时?  - 这首歌就像是在回应他
-You`ve been home for what, two hours? -It`s Iike an answer to his song.
看来你是真喜欢鲁克
You really Iike this guy.
是啊，我真傻
Yeah, I`m an idiot.
你得为他唱出来
You have to sing that for him.
偷偷唱给他听怎么样?
What if you sang to him in secret?
在舞会上，看
At the dance. Ta-da.
我知道贺卡有点俗，但是…
Okay, I know the card`s Iike, really cheesy, but....
哦，老天，我希望你能喜欢
Oh, God, I hope you Iike it.
安吉，这裙子真漂亮，但是你疯了吗?
Ange, it`s beautiful, but are you crazy?
不，你肯定是疯了
No, I know you`re crazy.
我没有
Am not.
- 他不喜欢我的话，怎么办?  - 你们都会戴面具的
-What if he doesn`t even Iike me? -You`II both be in disguise.
这是你的机会，看看他到底对你有没有感觉
It`s your chance to see if he was really flirting with you.
上次见面我没穿衣服，他肯定会想东想西
I was naked. Of course he was flirting.
为什么要折磨自己呢? 他肯定看不上我
And why even torture myself? It`s not Iike I can have him.
为什么不试试呢?告诉他你的心意
Why not? Tell him how you feel.
要是他也喜欢你，你可以摘下面具，  吐露爱意，他不会告诉格尔夫人的
If he feels the same way, you can reveal your hot self and he won`t tell Gail.
要是他不喜欢这首歌，你就一直把面具戴着
And if he hates the song, Ieave the disguise on.
好吧
Okay.
我决定参加舞会了
I`m going to the dance.
这才是好样的
That`s my girl.
摩利士，别这么画，再说一遍, 我要法式长腿
Maurice, no, no. Again, in Francais, Ionger Iegs.
我要是你的话就不会在衣橱里多呆一秒
I wouldn`t go in your closet for a Iittle while if I were you.
什么?为什么?
What? Why?
喂，不许睡
Hey. Wake up.
凯蒂!
GAIL: Katie!
猫在我衣橱里大便了，你去把它清干净
The cat has pooped in my closet. I need you to clean it up.
快走
Go.
我说过，我们没养猫
I told you we don`t have a cat.
安吉，快走
Angie, heads up.
凯蒂!
Katie!
发生什么事了?
What`s going on?
啥事也没有
Nothing.
我，额，在收拾东西
I am, uh, re-organizing and Iabeling. I....
我开始学针织了，你想要新袜子吗?
I took up crochet. Do you want new socks?
我本想给你织件线衣，但我听说织袖子特别难
I would make you a sweater, but I hear that the arms, that they`re really hard.
你以为自己可以偷偷溜出去参加舞会是吧
Oh, you thought you could sneak off and go to the dance.
觉得自己今天向盖伊伊展露才华了是吧
After what you pulled today with Guy.
不可以的
Oh, no, no.
绝对不可以
Oh, no, no, no.
你今晚要照看好维克特…
You`re on Victor watch tonight...
…明晚也是，每晚都是
...tomorrow night and every night.
有意思吧
Fun.
我会给维克特照顾得好好的，知道你没时间
I`II give Victor all the mothering you don`t have time for.
你要是我妈该多好
Oh, I wish you could be my mommy.
我要去吃肉桂熏肠了
I`m off to my cinnamon colonic.
[HIP-HOP MUSIC PLAYING ON STEREO]
喂，下来，你会摔着的
KATIE: Hey. Get down. You`re gonna break yourself.
要是破坏家具，那更糟
Or worse, the furniture.
- 有人吗?  - 嗨
ANGELA: Hello? -Hey.
- 看起来你很欢乐嘛  - 一向的
-You Iook Iike you`re having fun. -AIways.
我要你和我一起去舞会
Well, I couldn`t Iet you not go to the dance without me.
而且我们有6个小时可以看赤膊的雅各布  （暮光之城里的狼人，总共3部）
Besides, we have six hours of shirtless Team Jacob.
我们就去舞会吧
So Iet`s just get this party started.
- 维克特是不是让你很无语?  - 我发誓，他不是人
-So is Victor driving you nuts? -I swear to you, he`s not human.
我是说，难道你舍得怪他吗?  看看这个家是什么样子
I mean, can you really blame him, though? Just Iook at this family.
维克特，你要干嘛?
Victor, what are you doing?
[YELLS]
[LAUGHS]
哦，不，这下好了
Oh, no. Great.
她这样看起来漂亮多了
Eh, she actually Iooks prettier that way.
没错，让它去吧
KATIE: True. Ugh. Whatever.
为什么我会觉得今晚应该很特别
Why did I ever think that tonight could`ve been something special.
现在贝芙在舞会上肯定紧贴着鲁克吧?
Think Bev`s all over Luke at the dance right now?
他们可能已经亲上了，看这个
They`re probably making out. See?
- 维克特，别闹了  - 就看一眼，快
-Victor, give it a rest. -Just check it out. Come on.
鲁克会捧红任何在汇展上表现最好的人
Luke is gonna produce whoever wins the Showcase.
我们需要吃点定心丸
So we need a little insurance.
- 妈，我知道我要嘛  - 真的吗?
-I know what I`m doing, Mother. GAIL: Do you?
我受不了了
I can`t take it anymore, okay?
我要靠自己过想要的生活
I`m taking my Iife into my own hands.
我去找鲁克
I`m talking to Luke.
- 终于  - 好吧，可是我们必须在格尔回来之前…
-Finally. -Okay, but we have gotta be home...
…到家
... before Gail gets here.
这个小魔头咋办?
What about the demon spawn?
哼哼
Mm-hm.
说得是
KATIE: Right.
好吧，你看着他就行
Okay, just watch him.
哼
ANGELA: Hmm.
[BARKS]
[CHUCKLES]
你就这么点能耐么，安吉拉?
Is that all you`ve got, Angela?
拉维?
Ravi?
[SPORTS COMMENTATORS TALKING ON TV
[泽西口音]我妹都能接到那球，蠢货
RAVI [IN JERSEY ACCENT]: My sister could catch that, jerknut.
滚你的蛋吧，裁判
Put some nuts in that sack, ref.
[印度口音]凯蒂小姐，我很意外
[IN INDIAN ACCENT] Miss Katie, I am most startled.
显然如此
Obviously.
算了，好吧，你不要讨厌我
[IN JERSEY ACCENT] AII right. AII right. Don`t hate me.
别讨厌我好吗，我错了
Okay, don`t hate me. I`m sorry.
我不叫拉维，我是托尼
But my name ain`t Ravi. It`s Tony.
- 托尼  - 泽西岛的托尼·盖伊普塔
-Tony. -Tony Gupta from Jersey.
- 新泽西  - 我是半个印度人
-From Jersey. -I am half Indian.
因为我是印度混血，我朋友就叫我肉球
My friends call me Meatball because I`m half Italian.
其实我特别想当一名演员
Truth is I always wanted to be an actor.
但是从来没上过镜
But I never got my shot.
我本来在肯德基工作，一天，格尔夫人来了…
I`m working at KFC, and one day, Gail comes in...
…她说，"你是印度人吗?" 我说，"什么?"
...she`s Iike, ``Are you Indian?`` I`m Iike, ``What?``
她说，"你是古鲁（印度教精神导师）吗?"  我说：
She`s Iike, ``Are you a guru?`` I`m Iike:
"这就要看谁问了?"
[IN INDIAN ACCENT] ``Who is asking?``
她说："我要付钱做个精神指引"
[IN NORMAL VOICE] She says, ``Someone who`s paying for some spiritual guidance.``
我当时想："这真是奇迹!"
And I`m Iike, ``Whaa! It`s a miracle!``
我终于有机会全身心投入去演戏了
I finally get a chance to do a total immersion into a character.
锻炼演技，还有钱拿，天助我也啊
Real training and I get paid. Are you kidding me?
拉维就是我要演的角色
Ravi is my King Lear.
你想听《窈窕淑女》里的经典独白吗?
[IN ENGLISH ACCENT] You wanna hear the monologue from My Fair Lady?
- 噢，老兄  - 不用，谢了
-Oy, mate. -No, thanks.
对不起，我没打招呼就闯进来了
I`m sorry I barged in. Whoops.
[KATIE CHUCKLES]
我会替你保密的，但我也需要你帮忙
Your secret`s safe with me, okay? But I need to ask you a favor.
- 肉球  - 哈，肉球
-Meatball. -Ha, Meatball.
今晚请帮我看好维克特，这样我就能去参加舞会了
PIease watch Victor tonight so I can go to the dance?
这么点小事?没问题
Are you kidding me? Done.
[SIGHS]
一言为定
BIow it up.
[MIMICS EXPLOSION]
谢谢你
Thank you.
[CHUCKLES]
[INDIAN DANCE MUSIC PLAYING ON SPEAKERS]
哇噢
ANGELA: Whoa.
每个人都戴着面具，我怎么找鲁克啊?
KATIE: How am I supposed to find Luke if everybody`s got a mask?
我没说过这会很简单，我们先找找看
ANGELA: I never said this was gonna be easy. Let`s do some recon.
[CLEARS THROAT]
我是首席助理桃乐西·皮伯格
I am Assistant Principal Dorothy PIumberg.
不能喝酒，不能发短信，不能接吻
No drinking. No texting. No kissing.
鲁克?不是，鲁克·摩根?
Luke? No. Luke Morgan?
不能离开屋子，不能找乐子
No Ieaving the premises and no experiencing joy of any kind.
鲁克?
Luke? Ugh.
[KATIE SIGHS]
他在哪儿呢?
Where is he?
我想起来了，要你看场新表演
That reminds me. I got a new act for you to Iisten to.
- 现在?  - 择日不如撞日
-Now? -No time Iike it.
- 大哥，别这样  - 我们是大痛票乐队
-Dude, not again-- -We`re called Big Pain Ticket.
[CHAIN SAW REVVING]
天崩地裂也要吻你
I wanna kiss your apocalypse
海枯石烂也要拥抱你
Wrap you in my Armageddon
为你唱首拧巴的小夜曲
Sing you a twisted serenade
他们唱得不错，可是我担心那电锯不安全
They`re good, but I`m worried that chain saw`s unsafe.
大哥，我觉得那电锯才是亮点
Dude, the chain saw`s, Iike, the best part.
我想我找到他了
I think I found him.
金发男啊
ANGELA: Well, he is blond.
噢，老天，她来这干嘛?
Oh, my God, what is she doing here?
我讨厌这些年轻人疯来疯去的
I hate teenage desperation.
你来这干嘛?
What are you doing here?
亲爱的，赛猪想要赢得比赛…
Oh, honey, the prize pig doesn`t win the blue ribbon...
…可不能盖住它的第三大宝贵资产噢
...by covering up its third best asset.
这话什么意思，还有，你刚才把我比成猪了?
A, what does that even mean and, B, did you just call me a pig?
亲爱的，我看到你在…
Honey, I saw you making sweet Iove...
…餐桌上狂吃那盘瑞典肉丸
...to a plate of Swedish meatballs at the snack table.
机不可失，失不再来哦，亲
It`s now or never, babe.
- 万一她发现我了怎么办?  - 我去分散她的注意力，快走
-What if she recognizes me? -I`II distract her. Go.
- 是我对了还是是我对了?  - 你是对的
-So was I right or was I right? -You were right.
你品位不错，但要是敢再在男厕开试唱会…
You have very cool taste. Any more auditions in the men`s...
…你就被开除了
...and you`re fired.
- 我知道你的秘密  - 什么秘密?
-I know your secret. -Which secret is that?
我听到你在学校唱的歌了
I heard you sing at school.
你唱得很棒
You were amazing.
我认识你吗?
Do I know you?
- 我想让你看点东西  - 你叫什么名字?
-I wanna show you something. -What`s your name?
安吉拉，你在干嘛?
Angela, what are you doing?
我有个请求
I`d Iike to make a request.
今晚不会让你失望的，我保证
I will make your night. I promise.
凡·莱文斯威夫人
ANGELA: Miss Van R.
听说您年轻的时候想当一名舞者，是真的吗?
Is it true you wanted to be a dancer when you were younger...
但是听说您的舞跳得不怎么样?
...but were never good enough?
[SCOFFS]
谁跟你说的?
Who told you that?
[PLAYING UPBEAT INDIAN DANCE MUSIC]
[PEOPLE CHEERING]
挺有爱的
GAIL: Well, now, how Iovely.
不过我在菲律宾监狱里见过更好的，甜心
But I`ve seen better dancing in a Filipino prison, sugar.
CROWD: Oh!
真滴?我这可是舞池宣战噢
Really? Because I think I just challenged you to a dance battle.
[CHEERING]
鲁克·摩根先生能不能接下白色的免费电话?
Would Luke Morgan please pick up the white courtesy phone?
鲁克·摩根先生，白色的免费电话
Luke Morgan, white courtesy phone.
- 等等，那是什么?  - 你没见过吉他么?
LUKE: Hold on. What is that? KATIE: You`ve never seen a guitar before?
你竟然在这里藏了把吉他,还藏了什么好东西?
You hid a guitar in there. You hiding anything else?
跟我来
Follow me.
LUKE: Oh, wow.
女士，你动人的眼睛里流光溢彩，  但是这种美又略带调皮…
Madam, while your exquisite eyes tell of a radiant, but mischievous beauty...
…我已经迫不及待了
...I have grown impatient.
摘下你的面巾吧，我要知道真相
Off with your veil, so that I may know the truth.
不让是吧
Or not.
我希望这个回答能解开你所有的疑窦
I`m hoping this answers a Iot of your questions.
我可以看到，你眼里的闪光
[SINGING] I can see it from the spark in your eyes
你否认过的事，其实你深信不疑
You believe in all the things You`ve denied
你想要飞翔，就抛下所有烦恼
You wanna fly And leave your worries behind
不是吗?不是吗?
Don`t you? Don`t you?
现在我在轻叩你的心门
Well, now I`m knocking At your front door
我在寻找正确的答案
And I`m looking for the right cure
我还是有点不确定
I`m still a little bit unsure
好了，现在摘下面巾
Okay, now take off that veil.
还不行
Uh-uh.
[CHUCKLES]
[UPBEAT INDIAN MUSIC PLAYING ON SPEAKERS]
[STOMACH RUMBLING]
[GROANS]
坏了，要拉肚子了
I think I`ve blown something.
有人闻到肉桂的味道了吗?
Does anyone else smell cinnamon?
[GAIL GROANING]
让开，肥猪
GAIL: Move it, fatso.
你永远不知道会发生什么
[SINGING] You can never tell where this might go
好吧，你太厉害了，你得让我知道你是谁
Okay, you are blowing my mind. You have to show me who you are.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
- 我们得走了  - 什么?
-We have to go. -What?
- 走啊  - 不行，安吉
-Come. -No, Ange.
现在正是最关键的时刻
In the middle of a really big moment right now.
某人出了状况，现在在回家的路上
Someone had an accident and went home.
真的很对不起
KATIE: I`m so sorry.
什么?你…?
What--? You...?
喂，等下啊
Hey. Wait.
你到底是谁?
But who are you?
这儿，快，快，快
Over here. Go, go, go.
- 我们比她先到  - 爱死你了
-We beat her. -I Iove you for this.
这身保姆装很好看嘛
Interesting babysitting attire.
我该意识到你会在我背后搞小动作
I should`ve known you`d go behind my back again.
那个学宝拉·阿宝度的跟风女，  还想要分散我的注意力
And that Paula Abdul wannabe, trying to distract me.
别那样说她
Don`t talk about her Iike that.
[STOMACH RUMBLING]
要是我记得不错，你朋友想成为编舞吧
Your friend wants to be a choreographer, if memory serves.
要是她没被开除的话，倒是前途光明
She might`ve made a decent one if she hadn`t gotten herself expelled.
看来朱莉亚学院（著名艺术学院）她是别想进了
Guess she can kiss them Juilliard dreams goodbye.
听我说，你要我做什么我就做什么，成吗?  只要你别害安吉拉
Look, I`II do whatever you want. Okay? Just Ieave Ange out of this.
这得看你会不会再玩花招了,甜心
That depends if you pull another stunt Iike tonight, sugar.
- 我不会了  - 吉他我拿走了
-I won`t. -I`II be taking this.
[DOOR OPENS THEN CLOSES]
她的头巾把脸蒙住了，只能看到眼睛，  不过她的声音…
Only her eyes were piercing out through this veil, but her voice....
0～10打分的话，她能得几分?
How hot was the girl on a scale of one to 10?
- 11分  - 可最高就10分啊
-An 1 1. -The hotness scale only goes 10.
这个女孩很有潜质
Yeah, this girl has Iove potential.
- 还有爱  - 闭嘴
-Ooh, Iove. -Shut it.
我们会一直练下去，直到你配合好为止
We are gonna do this for hours until we get it right. Even if it takes hours.
好好唱，想着唱歌能保命，亲爱的，  因为它确实能
Now, sing Iike your Iife depends on it. Because, sugar, it does.
录音了
We`re recording.
插上麦克风
[SINGING] Plug in the mike
拉开窗帘
Open the curtain
打开灯
Turn on the lights
我在排练
I`m through rehearsing
- 她唱的很好啊，老兄  - 我就说吧
-Dang, she`s good, man. -Told you, man.
看看这个
Check this out, all right?
歌唱组里有39个女孩  也就是说，她们中有85%的人…
Thirty-nine girls in the singing program which means 85 percent...
…第6节是声乐课
...have music during the sixth period.
你看中的女生就在其中的一个教室里面
So your girl`s in one of those rooms.
激情点燃
The feeling ignites
我全部掌控
I`m in control
哦，打住，打住
Oh, cut. Cut.
这充其量只是中下水平
That was subpar at best.
从开头重来，唱好一点
From the top, pretty please.
迷人的优雅
GIRLS [SINGING]: Amazing grace
有意思，我上过这个课
It`s cool, I got this.
女士们，单身的女士们
Ladies, all my single Iadies.
我的哥们鲁克有事想请你们帮忙
My boy Luke here has a special favor to ask of you, all right?
即将到来的汇演上，他需要声乐表演
He needs vocals for this big show coming up, so....
- 我的名字是…  - 鲁克·摩根
-My name is-- -Luke Morgan.
你要让我上场的，你一定要
You will put me in the Showcase. Oh, yes, you will.
- 能不能先让我听听你唱歌?  - 我要震撼你的世界
-Maybe I could ask you to sing first? -I am so gonna rock your world.
我爱你爱我的方式，鲁克
[SINGING] I love the way you love me, Luke
每天晚上我都在想
Inside my head every night
你来跟我吻安
You come and kiss me good night
所见即所得
Whatever you see is what you get
你就不能认真点，再重唱一遍?
Why don`t you not suck and do it again, okay?
我想永远和你在一起…
I wanna be with you forever--
这里怎么回事?唱得真难听
PLUMBERG: What is going on in here? Disgusting.
你们两个男生不是我的学生,别走，等等
You two boys are not in my class. Stop. Wait.
别走，等等，停下来
Stop. Wait. Stop.
[GIRLS SCREAMING]
我一无所有
I got nothing to lose
我毫不遮掩
I`ve been exposed
我付出了代价
I`m paying my dues
承担责任
Playing the role
- 不是吧?  - 我们回到原来的地方了
-Oh, really? -We are back where we started.
这可不好
This is not good.
[KATIE SINGING NEARBY]
就是她，这是她的声音
That`s her. That`s her voice.
别以为你们可以从我眼皮下溜走
PLUMBERG: Don`t think you can get away from me.
- 让一让，让一让  - 请等等
-Step aside. Step aside. -PIease. Wait.
好吧，但是为什么不把试音带给我先
Okay. But first, why don`t you just both audition for me.
听着--
Listen--
鲁克，你就是我的唯一，我的唯一
[SINGING] Luke, you are the one for me, yes you are
可你还不懂我的心
You just don`t know it yet
[PLUMBERG SINGING OPERA]
让你相信我
[KATIE SINGING ON RECORDING] Make you believe in me
我会成为你想让我成为的人
I can be what you want me to be
就是今晚，我会让你见证
Tonight is the night Where I make you see
我可以成为任何人，任何人，任何人
[LIP-SYNCHING] That I can be Anything, anything, anything
我会让你相信
I`ll make you believe in me
我会成为你想要我成为的人
I can be what you want me to be
就是今晚，我会让你见证
Tonight is the night Where I make you see
[MUSIC STOPS]
那天晚上唱歌的是你?
It was you?
- 哦，不好意思打扰了  - 没关系，宝贝，继续打扰吧
-Oh, sorry to interrupt. -Oh, no, honey. Interrupt away.
我没想到我们能再见面，可想死我了，  因为我感觉我们有心灵感应
I didn`t think I`d see you. It was killing me. Because I felt Iike we connected.
[CLEARS THROAT]
不好意思，你们什么时候有的心灵感应?
Excuse me. Uh, how exactly did you two connect?
是啊，我们什么时候…我是说，我们确实有
Yeah, how did we? I mean, we did.
- 是通过…  - 你的歌词，它们…
-Through-- -With your Iyrics. They just--
- 让我无法忘怀  - 我的歌词，没错
-I can`t get them out of my head. -My Iyrics. Yeah.
是啊，多妙的事儿啊
GAIL: Well, how wonderful.
但是，贝芙需要准备为汇演准备试音
But, uh, Bev has to prepare for her Showcase audition.
她不需要试音的，你直接上了
Oh, no. She doesn`t need to audition. You`re in.
等下一起吃个饭吧?
Do you wanna grab a bite Iater?
- 好的  - 等等
-Yeah. PLUMBERG: Wait.
你放学后得留下来
You have a date with detention.
实际上，他和我有个约会
Actually, he has a date with me.
我的天啊，我还没开除你么?
Dear me, did I not fire you?
- 我有终身任职权  - 再有一个投诉电话，你滚去当服务员…
-I have tenure. -One call and you`re wearing a paper hat...
…"欢迎来到麦当劳，您想吃点什么?"  再有一个电话，你就滚了
...that says ``Welcome to McDonald`s. How may I take your order?``
- 再五个投诉电话  - 两个电话和一条短信
-Five calls. -Two calls and text.
两个电话，一条短信，几封电邮
Two calls, a text, several Iong e-mails.
- 一条短信和一条微博  - 一条短信和一条转发
GAIL: One text and a Tweet. -One text and a re-Tweet.
噢，看在上帝的份上，回去擦黑板吧
Oh, for God`s sakes, go Iick a chalkboard.
很好
Fine.
我恨你
I hate you.
好了，我想和你合作写首歌，今晚谈谈吧?
Okay. Um, I`d Iove to write a song with you. Let`s talk about it tonight?
- 好啊  - 好的，说好了啊
-I`d Iove to. -Okay, you`re on.
我一直都想写首歌
I`ve always wanted to write a song.
我可以写我的皮肤，据说爱情能细致毛孔
Maybe I`II write about my skin. They say Iove tightens your pores.
和毛孔押韵的词有什么?
What rhymes with pores?
琐事，无聊，疼痛
Chores. Bores. Sores.
凯蒂，你的新任务来了
Katie, I`ve got a new task for you.
极度失望吧
Crushing disappointment.
你得写首歌，让贝芙跟鲁克说是她写的
You are gonna write a song for Bev to say she wrote for Luke.
写首关于鲁克吻技高超的歌吧
A song about what a good kisser Luke is.
我们不能就给他首歌
GAIL: We can`t just give him a song.
他想和你合作写歌，可你对音乐一窍不通
He wants to write it with you and you know nothing about music.
凯蒂，真不好意思…
Katie, I`m sorry to say...
…贝芙需要你的帮助来留住你的男人
...but Bev`s gonna need some help keeping your man.
我是说，她的男人
Well, I mean, her man.
[BAND PLAYING SOFT JAZZ MUSIC]
噢，你那如丝缎般顺滑的高音，真的是…
Oh, and that silky smooth sound you hit on the high notes, that is just--
是我听过的最性感的声音
It is the sexiest thing I`ve ever heard.
顺滑又性感，讲的真好
Silky and sexy. That`s good. Ha, ha.
我不知道为什么，但我没想到你会喜欢音乐
I don`t know why, but I was kind of surprised that you were into music.
- 我也是  - 哈?
-Yeah, me too. -What?
我是说，我就喜欢音乐
I mean, I am.
你是不是有事? 一直在看手机
Are you okay? You keep checking your phone.
是的，额…
Yes. Um.... Um....
我奶奶摔倒了，盆骨骨折
My grandma fell and broke her hip.
所以她给我发短信，告诉我情况
So she just sends me updates.
- 老人家也爱玩手机  - 这样啊
-OId people and their cell phones. LUKE: Yeah.
- 所以我不想错过她的短信  - 我希望她没事
-So I just I don`t wanna miss anything. -I hope she`s okay.
但是，你说对了
But, uh, you were right.
我，我一直在隐瞒
I, um-- I have been hiding.
- 你的死讯?  - 哈?
-From your dead? -Sorry?
爸爸
[MOUTHS] Dad.
你爸爸
Dad.
[CHUCKLES]
- 瞒着你爸爸  - 是的
-Hiding from your dad. -Yes.
我们第一次见面的时候，你好像有些沮丧
You seemed upset that first day that we met.
我那时想，可能和你爸爸有些关系
And I thought maybe your dad had something to do with it.
他想让我跟他一样做生意，可我想玩音乐
He wants me to be just Iike him. And I wanna play music.
我不想成为那种管着音乐家的人
I don`t wanna be some suit managing musicians.
你感觉他希望你成为另外一种人?
You feel Iike he wishes you were a totally different person?
是的，有时我也希望我能
Yes. And sometimes I even wish that.
- 这个想法很白痴吧?  - 是的
-Does that sound stupid? -Yes.
啊?
Sorry?
我是说，一点也不
I mean, no.
一点也不
你最喜欢哪位音乐人?
LUKE: So who is your favorite artist?
现在喜欢的是麋鹿
Today, it would have to be Moose.
你说的是缪斯吧?
Do you mean Muse?
是啊，缪斯，我刚刚说的就是他
Yeah, Muse. That`s what I said.
噢
Oh.
但老歌必须是约翰·列侬的
But old-school would have to be John Lennon.
上帝，我也爱列侬，他的歌词好真诚
Oh, God, I Iove Lennon. His Iyrics are so honest.
他的声音就像一个角
His voice was just Iike an angle.
- 一个角?  - 是啊
-An angle? -Yeah.
你文盲啊
Learn how to read.
你知道的，就像是，一个直角一样
Yeah, it would be Iike, uh, a right angle, you know.
从90度出发
It would start out at 90 degrees.
然后就带你到你从没料想过的地方去
And then it would just take you somewhere that you never expected you would go.
[CHUCKLES]
- 没听懂，对吧?  - 完全不懂
-Doesn`t really make any sense, does it? -Not at all.
也许你可以问我别的问题
Maybe you could just ask me another question.
我说想和你一起写歌，是认真的
I wasn`t kidding when I said we should write together.
这可不是问题
That`s not a question.
[CHUCKLES]
噢，那好吧
Oh, okay.
那么激发你写歌的灵感是什么?
Um, how about what inspires you to write music?
灵感?问的真好
What inspires me? That`s a good question.
你知道，我得说，那是…
You know, I would have to say-- It would be, um....
灵感!
Inspiration!
Oh. Wow. Ahem.
你懂的，灵感是一种深层次的--
You know, inspiration is such a deeply, uh--
它是很私人的东西，无法用语言表达，就这样
It`s personal. It`s, Iike, kind of indefinable, I guess you could say.
它就是很私人的东西，哦，天哪
It`s just personal. Oh, my God.
- 我很抱歉  - 不，没关系
-I`m so sorry. LUKE: No, you`re okay. Um....
- 把你衣服弄脏了吗? 太对不起了
BEV: Did it get on your jacket? Oh, I`m so sorry.
- 不，你知道么? 没事的，只是--
LUKE: No, you know what? You`re fine. It`s just--
哦，不
Oh, no. Uh....
- 你奶奶还好吗?  - 她需要去个厕所
-Is Grandma okay? -Uh, no. Um, she has to go to the bathroom.
- 她确实什么都跟你说  - 我也要去一下厕所
-Oh, she does tell you everything. BEV: I should go to the bathroom too.
[CHUCKLES]
我马上回来
I`II be right back.
你在干嘛?给我回去，发的短信像咒语一样难念
What are you doing? Get back out there. This is working Iike a charm.
你还想让我怎么样?发信号弹?
What do you want me to do? Send smoke signals?
- 当然不是  - 你总可以坐回去吧?
-No. -Look, you can go back in there, okay?
但你就是胡言乱语，你都不知道我说什么
But you are so in over your head you don`t even know it.
我才没有，你知道吗?
No, I`m not. You know what?
我才不要说你的话了，不需要你了
I`m so sick of using your words. I don`t need you.
我自己可以，鲁克需要我
I can do this on my own. Luke wants me.
我很会说话的
I talk good.
好吧，祝你好运
Hey, good Iuck.
- 嗨  - 不好意思
-Hi. -Sorry.
我们来谈谈古典音乐吧，你最喜欢谁的?
So Iet`s talk classical music. Who are your favorites?
莫扎特?
Mozart.
贝多芬?
Beethoven?
是柴可夫斯基，你肯定喜欢天鹅湖，是不?
Tchaikovsky. You are a Swan Lake girl, aren`t you?
- 我有个坏消息，我奶奶死了  - 哦，天哪!深表哀悼
-I have bad news. My grandma croaked. -Oh, my God, I`m so sorry.
- 我得走了  - 我说，你要是想谈谈，我…
-I should go. -Look, if you wanna talk about it, I--
谢谢，我更想一个人默默回忆我奶奶
You know, I would prefer to remember my grandma`s memory in silence.
[GIGGLES]
该死
Crap.
Mah-meh, mah-meh.
维克特，要是你敢再偷我那把纪念甘地的小刀…
GAIL: Victor, if you have stolen my commemorative Gandhi knife again...
…我就把你阉了
...I will make you into a eunuch.
你应该看好维克特的
You were supposed to be watching Victor.
您刚才说想让这些吊灯闪亮亮的
You told me you wanted the chandelier to sparkle.
现在我要你把这张没脑袋的破画扔掉
Now I want you to throw out my facelessness.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
维克特，贝芙在家吗?
Victor, is Bev in?
能猜出我唱的是什么歌,我就告诉你
[SINGING] I`ll tell you When you can guess what song I`m playing
贝芙在家吗?
Is Bev in?
猜歌!
Guess what song!
这不像我听过的任何一首歌!
It doesn`t sound Iike anything I`ve ever heard!
这是因为我不知道怎么弹!你可以猜一整天!
That`s because I don`t know how to play! We could be here all day!
好吧，我可以教你弹几个和弦!
Well, I could show you some chords!
- 我以为你要见贝芙  - 等会儿再找她
-I thought you wanted to see Bev. -Bev can wait a sec.
- 好的  - 好吧?
-Okay. -Yeah?
现在，我要教你三个和弦
Now, I`m gonna show you three chords.
- 我们用这三个和弦弹奏一首歌  - 好
-And we`re gonna turn it into a song. -Okay.
这是第一个和弦
This is the first chord.
E调
It`s an E.
很好，第二个
AII right. Second chord.
G调，弹一下
Go to G. SIide it up.
恩，好了
Oh, yeah. Okay.
我们继续，再次弹一下， 这是A调
There we go. SIide it up again. You got an A.
现在，我们把这三个和弦组合起来
There. We`re gonna put it together.
- 就成了一首歌  - 噢好
-It`s gonna be a whole song. -Okay.
你弹
Now.
[PLAYING CHORDS]
非常好，你可以弹歌了，小家伙
Very good. You can play, you rascal.
你要是多练习，加上这个发型，就是披头士了
If you practice and with that haircut, you could be a Beatle.
不，滚石乐队更好
No, The Stones are a Iot better.
- 鲁克  - 嗨
-Luke. -Hey.
- 嗨  - 我总是在这碰到你
KATIE: Hi. -I keep running into you here.
但这次穿好衣服了
But no partial nudity this time.
额，我不知道你和贝芙今天有约
Um, I didn`t know you and Bev had a date today.
是没有，我要给她个惊喜
Oh, yeah. No, I`m kind of surprising her.
我去找她
I`II go get her.
他很疯
He`s crazy.
这幅画貌似没有头
So it Iooks Iike she Iost her head.
是啊，这是某位艺术家的杰作，  主题是，这是什么状况
Oh. Yeah, it`s an artist`s rendition of what`s going on up there.
你用的是加拉赫吉他
You play a Gallagher.
真酷
That is so cool.
- 你懂吉他  - 不懂
-You know guitars. -No. Uh-uh.
我是说，知道一点，就一点
I mean, yeah, a Iittle. Not really.
没错，我喜欢红木的共鸣箱，护住……
Yeah, I know. I Iike the way the, um-- The rosewood holds the, uh....
- 琴弦  - 琴弦
-The notes. -Notes.
琴弦，是的
Notes, yeah. Um....
你貌似总是不见人影，其实我希望你别走
You always seem to disappear. I really wish you wouldn`t.
你很有个性
You`re actually quite cool.
你觉得我有个性?
You think I`m cool?
鲁克，好啊
Luke. Hi.
真是惊喜
-What a surprise. -Um--
- 噢，天哪，我喜欢你的紧身牛仔裤  - 谢谢，我…
-Oh, God, I Iove your skinny jeans. -Oh, thank you. Uh....
我把吉他带来了，我们可以一起写歌
I brought my guitar. We could write that song.
- 太好了  - 恩
-Awesome. Yeah. -Okay.
哦，好吧，我想我得消失了
Oh, yeah. I guess I gotta go disappear.
你能在这等一分钟吗?
And can you just wait in there for one minute?
- 我需要你的新歌  - 什么?我还没写完呢
-I need your new song. -What? I`m not done yet.
写了多少给我多少
Give me what you have so far.
- 快点  - 不要伤害我的心
-Come on. -Don`t break my heart.
我要伤害的可不止这些，快给我点料
I will break more than that.
- 不是，这是歌词  - 啊?
-No, that`s the Iyric. -What?
就一句?
That`s it?
你有那么多时间写歌，天哪，我抽筋了
You have had forever to work on this. Oh, my God, you`re giving me a twitch.
[BEV PANTING]
有了
Fine.
维克特?
BEV: Victor?
- 维克特  - 维克特
-Victor. -Victor.
我知道你在这
BEV: I know you`re there.
你们非法入侵了一个充满伤痛的世界
You`re trespassing and you`ve just entered a world of hurt.
好吧，维克特，我对你那些监控的破玩意儿，  知道的一清二楚
Yeah, well, I know all about your surveillance crap, Victor.
你的摄像头隐藏在房间的每一个角落
Your cameras hidden in every nook and cranny, I know.
- 什么角落?  - 你有证据么?
-What kinds of nooks and crannies? -You can`t prove anything.
你要是肯不帮我，我就告诉妈妈
Well, I won`t tell Mom if you do me a favor.
我要凯蒂在不被人听到的情况下跟我说话
I need Katie to talk to me with no one knowing.
- 别人听不到她，但她能听到我  - (别答应她)
-No one can hear her. She can hear me. [MOUTHS] Don`t.
- 可以吗?  - (别答应)
-Is it possible? -Say no.
你找对人了
You`ve come to the right man.
看好了，女士们
Watch and Iearn, Iadies.
[BEEPING]
我可以在任何地方藏话筒
I can hide a mike anywhere.
妈妈吞了一个
Mom swallowed one.
相信我，你肯定不想听她胃里消化食物的声音
And you don`t wanna hear the Iive feed, trust me.
这太疯狂了
Oh, this is insane.
我保证万无一失
I guarantee my work.
- 维克特，让凯蒂准备好  - 好
-Hey, Victor, set up Katie. -Okay.
这是你的，凯蒂
Here you go, Katie.
我把这放在耳朵里?
I put this in my ear?
挂在耳朵上，然后说话
You put it on your ear and you talk.
你这么丑，这里的东西都适合你
Well, you are ugly, you could probably fit all it in there.
久等了，鲁克
Luke, I`m so sorry.
我需要跟凯蒂谈点姐妹之间的事情
I have to give Katie a sisterly talk, you know.
她还真能说
She`s so high-maintenance. Ha, ha.
总之，我们刚才说到哪儿了?
Anyway, well, where were we?
噢，我们还没开始聊呢
Uh, well, we hadn`t started.
- 很好，现在开始吧  - 贝芙
-Perfect. Let`s start. KATIE: Bev.
贝芙，你能听到我吗?
Uh, Bev, hey, can you hear me?
- 你想要从哪儿说起?  - 贝芙?
-What do you wanna start with? KATIE: Bev?
- 在  - 恩?
-Yes. -What?
什么啊?
What? Ha.
你唱歌，我给你伴奏?
LUKE: You wanna sing and I`ll play harmony?
不要，要不你来唱…
Uh, no. I was thinking maybe you could sing...
…我会给你一些我写的歌词
...and I could give you some Iyrics that I wrote.
- 这个主意不错，好的
LUKE: That sounds good, okay.
- 我…额…  - 那就好
-I.... Um.... BEV: Yeah.
歌词是…
They are, um.... Um....
不要伤我的心
Don`t break my heart.
在我把心交给你之前
Before I give it to you.
不要伤我的心，在我把心交给你之前，不错
Don`t break my heart before I give it to you, okay.
- 不要对我说不  - 不要对我说不
KATIE: Don`t tell me no. -Don`t tell me no.
在我开口问你之前
Before I ask you to.
BEV: Before I ask you to.
不要对我说不，在我开口问你之前
Don`t tell me no, before I ask you to.
- 是  - 很好啊
-Yeah. -That`s good. Um....
谢谢夸奖
Thanks.
不要伤我的心
LUKE: Don`t break my heart.
[HUMMING]
还有吗?
LUKE: More?
不要说不合适
Don`t say it doesn`t fit.
在你尝试之前
Before you try it on.
不要说不合适，在你尝试之前
Don`t say it doesn`t fit before you try it on.
尝试之前
BEV: Try it on.
- 这词我喜欢  - 谢谢
-I Iike it. -Thanks. Ha, ha.
如果错了
Um, there`s too much to Iose.
- 错了的话  - 如果错了
-There`s so much to Iose. KATIE: Too much to lose.
如果错了
Too much to Iose.
- 你会失去很多  - 你会失去很多
KATIE: To be wrong. -To be wrong.
如果错了，你会失去很多
Too much to Iose to be wrong.
- 这词写的好  - 是嘛?
-Yeah. That`s good. BEV: Yeah.
还有吗?你还有写吗?
More? You got any more?
- 有啊  - 感觉心里有些什么
BEV: Yeah. -And it feels Iike there`s something here.
感觉心里有些什么
BEV: And it feels Iike there`s something here.
And it feels Iike there`s something here.
我想在它消失之前得以瞥见
But I wanna see it before it disappears.
- 很好  - 喜欢吗?
-Yeah. BEV: Do you Iike that?
[BEV CHUCKLES]
若你我之间是真实的存在
And if there`s something real between me and you.
BEV: And if there`s something real between me and you.
- 若你我之间是真实的存在…  - 我们能否坦诚吐露
LUKE: If there`s something real between-- -Or are we both open to.
不要伤我的心，在我把心交给你之前
[SINGING] Don`t break my heart before I give it to you
不要对我说不，在我开口问你之前
Don`t tell me no before I ask you to
不要说不合适，在你尝试之前
Don`t say it doesn`t fit before you try it on
如果错了，你会失去很多
There`s too much to lose to be wrong
感觉心里有些什么
And it feels like there`s something here
我想在它消失之前得以瞥见
But I wanna see it before it disappears
若在你我之间是真是的存在
And if there`s something real Between me and you
那么，我们能否坦诚吐露
Well, are we both open to
这所有的可能啊
All these possibilities
这么多的小可能
So many little possibilities
有人想吃馅饼吗?
KATIE: Who wants pie? BOTH: Ugh!
对不起，我准备去拿些馅饼，就在想…
Sorry. Um, I was just gonna go get some pie and thinking:
既然我要给自己拿馅饼，为什么不给大家也拿一块?
``Why should I get pie for myself. There might be other people that want some pie?``
我要馅饼
I want pie.
不要，凯蒂，现在这儿没人要馅饼，谢谢
No, Katie, there`s no pie needs here at the moment. Thank you.
我想我得走了
You know what? I should go.
还有些为汇演准备的表演需要我确定下
Um, I`ve got some acts to finalize for the Showcase so I`II, uh--
我们刚才在唱歌，我们在一起做事
We were singing. And we were doing things.
每一件事都很棒
And it was amazing. AII of it.
改天联系你，好吗?
And I`II catch you Iater, okay?
好，我送你
Okay, I`II walk you out.
- 好的  - 好
-Okay. -Okay.
[SOBBING]
[KATIE SHRIEKS]
您在我的床上干嘛?
What are you doing in my bed?
等你的时候，我发奋冥想，结果睡着了
While waiting for you, I meditated so strenuously that I fell asleep.
维克特少爷，现在是每周冥想时间
[AS RAVI] Mr. Victor, time for your weekly meditation.
今天我们要练习保持安静和控制小便
Today, we are working on, uh, silence and potty training.
坐下
GAIL [OVER MONITOR]: Oh, sit.
我说了，坐下
I said sit.
布凡维舍利神的名字有什么寓意?
What in the name of Bhuvaneshwari?
[GAIL CLEARS THROAT]
我的天啊
Holy cow.
在我喝那瓶酒之前，本想展示我的菩萨心肠
uh, a bottle of wine ago, I was gonna be sweet as sugar...
为我当了个坏继母而道歉
...and apologize for Iiving up to the stereotype of stepmotherhood.
愚蠢的想法
Dumb.
我让你眼看着我的亲生女儿偷走你爱的男生…
You know, but making you watch my real daughter steal the boy you like...
以及你写的歌
...and the song you wrote.
你感到内疚了?
You`re saying you`re sorry?
噢，上帝保佑，没，没，没
Oh, bless your heart. No, no, no.
待我清醒之后，觉得只想跟你说实话
I came to my senses and I realized it was better to just tell you the truth.
你永远不会有出息的
You are never gonna amount to anything.
我妈就是个贱女人
My mom is a beyotch.
而你是个鬼鬼祟祟的间谍，维克特少爷
And you`re a sneaky, sneaky spy, Mr. Victor.
你装了多少摄像头?
How many cameras do you have?
多到能知道你的印度口音比我妈的灵魂还要假
Enough to know your accent`s faker than my mom`s soul.
你别蠢到去搞砸汇演
Oh, and don`t get the dumb idea to throw that Showcase.
因为我咨询了律师
Because I talked to a Iawyer.
他找到了漏洞，能让我把你爸留给你的钱拿走
And he found a Ioophole that allows me to access that money your daddy Ieft you...
我只需要说是治病的
...should I need it for a medical reason.
这样我就可以去整我的大长腿了
You know, hello, longer legs.
- 慢着，在你走之前…  - 我会为贝芙唱歌的，别担心
-Whoa, whoa, whoa. Before you go-- -I`II sing for Bev. Don`t worry.
这比我设想的要容易多了
Well, that was easier than I thought.
现在去给我倒杯伏特加酒
Now, go and make me a vodka tonic.
把酒端稳了
Hold the tonic.
[BOTH GROAN]
她的恐怖统治该结束了
[IN NORMAL VOICE] Her reign of terror`s gotta stop.
我也觉得，我们怎么做?
I`m in. What do we do?
听我说，你们什么都不能做
Look, there`s nothing you can do.
你们帮忙只会让事情变得更糟
If you try to help, it`s just gonna make it worse.
那女人就是个恶魔的代言人
That woman is a demon spawned from darkness itself.
我真希望她能直接下地…
I wish she`d go straight back to--
您好，格尔夫人
[AS RAVI] Hello, Ms. Gail.
今天您从思考的束缚里解脱了吗?
Have you, uh, released your mind from the shackles of thinking today?
- 我正在为此努力  - 非常好
-I`m working on it. -Very good.
- 您的冥想效果如何?  - 我嫌弃你
-How was your meditation? GAIL: I hate you.
非常好，您看起来很美
Very good. You Iook pretty.
那是
I know.
她不毁了你的生活就不会罢休
[IN NORMAL VOICE] That broad ain`t getting away with ruining your Iife.
我今晚要在她的床上大便
I`m pooping in her bed tonight.
维克特，我还以为你讨厌我
Victor, I thought you hated me.
你傻啊?
Are you an idiot?
你是唯一记得我生日的人
You`re the only person who knows my birthday.
唯一对我说晚安的人
The only one who says goodnight to me.
唯一为我做干酪通心粉的人
The only one who makes me mac and cheese.
你又丑又烦…
You`re annoying and ugly...
…但是我还是有点爱你
...but I sort of Iove you.
我也有点爱你
I sort of Iove you too.
但是你要向我保证，啥都别做
But just promise me you`re not gonna do anything, okay?
- 你也是  - 别这样
-You too. -Oh, come on.
- 就做一点点  - 不
-Just-- No-- PIe-- -Just-- No. Just--
- 不要，托尼  - 就…
-No. Tony. -Just one--
好吧
Okay.
很好，现在我得去给贝芙叠衣服了
AII right. Well, now I get to go fold Bev`s delicates.
[VICTOR YELLING]
[DOOR OPENS THEN SLAMS]
- 你不会敲门吗?  - 我管你啊
-Have you heard of knocking? -Ever heard of I don`t care?
你把我的蓝色短衫放哪儿了?
Where`d you put my blue blouse?
好的
Oh, okay.
这两件你觉得我穿哪一件好看?
Okay, which one of these do you Iike better?
- 你也需要我的建议了?  - 天哪，我也知道不对劲，我是怎么了?
-You actually want my opinion? -God, I know. What`s wrong with me?
你很贱，我装作不在意，是因为我内心敏感吗?
You know how you`re a bitch and I act Iike I don`t care, but truth is I`m sensitive?
- 其实…  - 我需要有个姐妹说说心里话…
-Actually-- -I need someone to talk to Iike a sister...
…有你总比没有好
...and you`re better than nothing.
我很紧张，天哪，我干嘛告诉你啊?
I`m nervous about tonight. Oh, my God, why did I just tell you that?
我不知道
I don`t know.
我整个人就要抓狂了
It`s Iike my whole body is freaking out.
我如坐针毡啊
I have hives on my butt.
我不能跟妈妈讲，也不能跟鲁克说
I can`t tell Mom and I can`t talk to Luke about it.
他肯定会说：
He`II say something Iike:
"有时候你很有才，我们心有灵犀…
[IN ENGLISH ACCENT] ``Oh, one minute you`re talented and we`re connecting...
…有时候你又很自我，装腔作势"
...and the next minute you`re self-involved and histrionic.``
- 他说这话什么意思? 我讨厌谈论历史  - 他这么说过吗?
-What does that even mean? I hate history. -He said that?
听着，癞蛤蟆，他不会爱上你，他爱的是我
Listen, Toadie, he`s not falling for you, he`s falling for me.
我都找不到自我了
I just don`t know who me is anymore.
你有什么好紧张的? 又不用你真唱
Why are you nervous? You`re not really singing.
你只需要美美的站在那里
AII you have to do is stand there and Iook pretty.
我的感受你想过没有?
Have you ever thought about how that makes me feel?
你有才
You have talent.
你可以去上美国偶像，然后甩了我们
You could go on American Idol and forget about the rest of us.
而这是我唯一的机会
This is, Iike, my only chance.
再漂亮也有老的时候
Pretty doesn`t Iast very Iong.
看看我妈就知道了
Just Iook at Mom.
你觉得我有才?
You think I`m talented?
你要是敢告诉别人，我会否认的
If you tell anyone I said that, I`II deny it.
穿蓝色短衫吧
Wear the blue blouse.
它能凸显你的眼睛的美
It makes your eyes pop.
最好是这样
This better work.
因为要是我砸了，你也不会有好下场
Because if I go down, you`re go down with me.
[UPBEAT ELECTRONIC MUSIC PLAYING]
[CROWD CHEERING]
很好很好，参加聚会的朋友们，你们好吗?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. What`s up, my party people?
好的，好的，表演现在就开始
Yeah. AII right, all right, all right. Let`s get this show started.
欢迎上台，我的英国小伙儿，也是今晚的主持…
Welcome to the stage, my boy, my British biscuit and y`all`s host for the night...
鲁克·摩根
...Luke Morgan.
[CROWD CHEERING]
威尔斯利音乐学院的艺术汇演，准备好了吗?
Are you amped for the Wellesley Academy of the Arts Showcase?
很好，今晚我们有米奇·欧马利负责打碟
Good. Because we have Mickey O`Malley spinning tonight.
今晚开场的表演来自大痛票乐队!
So Iet`s get this party started with Big Pain Ticket.
[CHAIN SAW REVVING]
天崩地裂也要亲吻你
I wanna kiss your apocalypse
海枯石烂也要拥抱你
Wrap you in my Armageddon
为你唱首拧巴的小夜曲
Sing you a twisted serenade
我们可以一起私奔
We can run away together
[REPORTERS CHATTERING]
噢，盖伊，真高兴您能来
Hello, Guy. So glad you could make it.
这是我A&R的两个下属，汤姆和汤姆
My two A&R guys, Tom and, uh, Tom.
我错过最精彩的部分了吗?
Uh, did I miss your big Iine up?
您来的正是时候，您肯定会喜欢压轴表演的  她唱的很好
You`re just in time. And I know you`II Iove the closing act. She`s amazing.
很好，希望不要让我失望
Well, I expect nothing Iess.
没错，没料和劣质正好形容她的表演
Oh, yeah. Nothing and Iess are definitely two words I`d use to describe it.
请您和两位汤姆先生到贵宾席就坐吧
Why don`t I show you and the Toms to the VIP section.
凯蒂，去后台帮贝芙化妆
Katie, go help Bev with her makeup, please.
- 好  - 现在就去
-Okay. -Now.
这边请
This way, please, come on.
您的西装真不错
What a Iovely suit.
让开
Move it.
让开，别挡道，麦克，这边
Hey. Out of the way. Out of the way. Michael, go on.
我需要去报幕，演出结束了我来找您
I have to announce what`s next. I`II see you at the end.
盖伊，汤姆，汤姆
Guy. Tom. Tom.
我很快就来
I`II be right back.
很高兴见到你
[AS RAVI] Good to see you.
西装不错
Nice suit.
你刚才演的哪一出啊? 最后给你一次机会
What was that back there? This is your Iast chance to get it right.
除非你想要安吉拉进不了朱莉亚学院
Unless you wanna see Angela`s Juilliard dreams go bye-bye.
那就是你想要的?让一个亚洲小矮人的梦碎了?
That what you wanna be? A Iittle dwarfish Asian girl`s dream crusher, huh?
- 你想这样吗?  - 不，不想
-Do you? -No. No.
不想?那就给我认真点!
No? No? No? Then focus!
- 安吉，你…  - 格尔也一直威胁我
-Look, Ange, you-- -Gail`s been threatening me too.
这就是为什么你要这样做
That`s why you`re doing what she wants.
- 为了保护我  - 安吉
-To protect me. -Ange.
你是我最好的朋友
You`re my best friend.
我会为你做任何事
Look, I`d do anything for you.
[CROWD CHEERING]
很好
Okay.
接下来我们有请杰森·伯克莱和胆小鬼乐队!
So we`re gonna take it up a notch with Jason Berkeley and the Funky Funk.
[GAGS]
先跳过去
Scratch that.
好，接下来有请，"口头多数"乐队!
Um, here are my boys, the Oral Majority.
[CROWD CHEERING]
我迷失在这个世界，它让我头脑发懵
[SINGING] I`m lost in a world that rattles my brain
我要整理自己的生活，清除你制造的混乱
Cleaning up my life From the mess you made, oh, oh
让让，盖伊
GAIL: Move it. Guy.
这只是乏味的开头，好戏在后面
This is just the boring appetizer. The real showstopper`s up next.
GUY: Ah! GAIL: Oh!
你没事吧，摩根先生?让我帮您擦吧
You okay, Mr. Morgan? Here, Iet me get that for you.
最好是很精彩
Well, it had better be.
我想尿尿
I have to pee.
我带你去厕所，维克特少爷
Oh, I will take you to the pee, Mr. Victor.
对不起
[WHISPERS] Sorry.
继续敲吧，敲吧，敲吧
So keep on knocking, knocking, knocking
但是宝贝，你最好知趣地走开，  因为我不会再让你走进我心
But, baby, you`re better off walking `Cause I ain`t gonna let you in
绝对不会
Never again
不，再也不会
No, not again
绝对不会
Never again
再也不会
No, not again
[CROWD CHEERING]
我的兄弟们，唱得好!
My brothers, yeah!
好的
LUKE: Okay.
朋友们，开心吗?
You guys having a good time?
晚会还在继续，有请贝芙莉·凡·莱文斯威
Let`s keep it going with Beverly Van Ravensway.
[UPBEAT POP MUSIC PLAYING ON SPEAKERS]
插上麦克
[LIP-SYNCHING] Plug in the mike
来开窗帘
Open the curtain
打开灯
Turn on the lights
我在排练
I`m through rehearsing
激情点燃
The feeling ignites
我全部掌控
I`m in control
人群握在我的掌心，我的歌迷站起来
The crowd`s in the palm of my hand All my fans stand
什么是真实?什么又是幻觉?
What is the truth? What`s an illusion?
你在寻找证明，但你能确定吗?
You`re searching for proof But are you certain?
所见即所得
Whatever you see is what you get
如果言语编织成画，那我定能为你画幅画
If words paint a picture Then I bet you I can get you, yeah
我会让你相信
I`ll make you believe in me
我能成为你想让我成为的人
I can be what you want me to be
就是今晚，我会让你看到
Tonight is the night Where I`ll make you see
我可以成为任何人，任何人，任何人
That I can be Anything, anything, anything
我会让你相信
I`ll make you believe in me
我能够成为…
I can be what you want--
[SINGING STOPS]
[VICTOR CHEERS]
快给我…
KATIE: Give me--
[CROWD BOOING]
太对不起了，我的麦…我的麦克风坏了
I`m so sorry, my mike-- My mike isn`t working.
不好意思
Uh, excuse me.
- 我不知道  - 给我，把它给我
[MOUTHS] I don`t know. -Give me that. Give me that.
[GALE GASPS]
[VICTOR GRUNTING]
你竟敢破坏妈妈的计划，你个坏小子?
How dare you sabotage your mother, you rotten, rotten Iittle boy?
你，把麦克风给我，还有别的法子
You, give me that. It doesn`t matter.
- 我们现场唱  - 什么?
-We`II do it Iive. -What? What?
我的麦克风坏掉了，对不起
Ha. My mike is broken. I`m so sorry.
站这儿
Here.
[MUSIC STOPS]
什么?
What?
呆在这儿
Stay.
[CROWD BOOING]
不不不，你快走，离开这里
No, no, no. You gotta get out of here.
你要帮贝芙唱歌，为什么要这样?
You`re about to sing for Bev. Why are you about to sing for Bev?
她不会唱
She can`t sing.
[CROWD BOOING]
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
走吧
BEV: Come on.
你们所有人，继续伴奏
Hey. AII of you, keep playing.
继续啊，蠢货们
Keep playing, you idiots.
原来一直都是你在唱，贝芙从没唱过?
It was your voice the whole time? Bev never sang at all?
[MUSIC RESUMES AND CROWD CHEERS]
她现在没在唱了，台下乱了，请你…
And she`s about to not sing for a whole bunch of people, so please--
那天晚上，是你…
And on the dates, that-- That was you.
我一无所有
[SINGING] I got nothing to lose
我毫不遮掩
I`ve been exposed
我付出了代价
I`m paying my dues
承担起责任
Playing the role
我要破坏规则
I`m breaking the rules
鼓动人群
Flow in the flow
我让全世界点头，没错，就像点头娃娃
I got the whole world nodding, yes Like some bobbleheads
我能不费吹灰之力
I`ll break a sweat
如果你想要如此
If you want it
承认你所有的过错
Confess all your sins
你知道你曾经犯过
You know you got `em
房间里天旋地转
The room`s in a spin
温度攀升
The fever`s pitched
你得到台前去，快去
-You gotta go. Come on, get out there. KATIE: Aah!
我有真材实料，而非假冒
I`m legit, I`m no counterfeit
我会让你相信
I`ll make you believe in me
我可以成为你想让我成为的人
I can be what you want me to be
就是今晚，我会让你看到
Tonight is the night where I make you see
我可以成为任何人，任何人，任何人
That I can be Anything, anything, anything
我会让你相信
I`ll make you believe in me
我可以成为你想要我成为的人
I can be what you want me to be
喂，把摄影机关了，马上!
Hey! Shut that camera down! Now!
就是今晚，我会让你看到
Tonight is the night where I make you see
我可以成为任何人，任何人，任何人
That I can be Anything, anything, anything
任何你想要我成为的人
You want from me
[CROWD CHEERING]
这才对嘛
That`s what I`m talking about.
关掉电源，关掉
Shut the power down. Shut it down.
[GAIL GRUNTS]
不要这么快嘛，蠢货
[IN NORMAL VOICE] Not so fast, jerknuts.
[TONY GRUNTS]
来个电击吧
Hey. CIear.
[GAIL SCREAMS]
- 再唱一首吧  - 再来一首!再来一首!
LUKE: Sing something else. CROWD: We want more! We want more!
唱什么呢?
Like what?
你给我爸试音带里的那首，我听了
The demo you snuck my dad. I heard it.
- 是啊，唱吧!  - 唱吧!
ANGELA: Yeah, do it! LUKE: Do it!
人们: 再来一首!再来一首!再来一首!
CROWD: We want more! We want more! We want more!
[CROWD CHEERING]
好吧，跟着我弹，兄弟们
Okay, follow my Iead, guys.
[PLAYING UPBEAT ROCK]
我想告诉你一个小秘密
There`s a little secret I would like to tell you
他们想要兜售你一本满是谎言的书
There`s a book of lies I know they`ll try to sell you
他们会尽力，尽力骗你买下它
And they`ll try and they`ll try To convince you to buy
骗你说你需要它
You need them
所以下次情绪低落时，不要向外寻求，  要向内自省
So the next time you`re down Look inside, not around
我可以自食其力
I can dress myself
不需要谁的垂怜
There`s no need for someone`s help
不必指责谁
There`s no one to blame
不必拯救谁，除了你自己
There`s no one to save you but yourself
我可以为自己辩解
I can justify
为我犯下的错
All the mistakes in my life
它教育了我，它滋养了我
It`s taught me to be It`s given to me
让我得以幸存
And I`ll survive
因为我为自己祈福
`Cause I have blessed myself
你有没有想过究竟为何哭泣?
Do you ever wonder How anything can make you cry?
你有没有发现
Have yourself discover
你在承受你不想承受的痛苦?
That the pain you feel Is the pain that you deny
你可以为自己祈福
You can bless yourself
不需要他人垂怜
There`s no need for someone else
不必指责谁，不必拯救谁，除了你自己
There`s no one to blame There`s no one to save you but yourself
我可以辩解
I can justify
为我犯下的错
All the mistakes in my life
它教育了我，它滋养了我
It`s taught me to be It`s given to me
让我得以幸存
And I`ll survive
因为我为自己祈福
`Cause I have blessed myself
[CROWD CHEERING]
感谢今天到场的女士们和先生们
ANNOUNCER: Thank you, Iadies and gentlemen.
希望你们度过了一个愉快的夜晚
We hope you enjoyed the Wellesley Academy of Arts Showcase.
噢，老天，你太棒了
ANGELA: Oh, my God, you were so good.
我都不认识你了，你就是个摇滚明星
Who are you? You`re Iike a freaking rock star.
不是开玩笑吧，老哥，她喜欢你
Are you kidding me? Man, she Iikes you--
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
你爸爸说什么了，他生气了吗?
So, what did he say? Is he mad?
是的，他责备我…
Yeah. He`s pretty ticked off...
…还没有给肯星顿唱片公司再做出张好专辑
...that I`m not already making the next big album for Kensington Records.
做什么专辑?
Oh. Which album?
你的专辑
Your album.
- 你不是逗我玩的吧?  - 绝对不是
-Are you kidding me? -No.
- 你们…你们是认真的?  - 对啊
-You`re-- You`re serious? -Uh-huh.
[CHUCKLES]
看好你们哦
VICTOR: Go for it.
我们要出专辑了，而且还会一起写歌
We`re making an album. And we`re writing it together.
- 好啊!好啊!  - 我太开心了
MICKEY: Yeah! Yeah! ANGELA: I`m so happy.
你知道吗，我也唱歌的
TONY: You know, I sing too.
- 我可以出一整张独白专辑  - 真难以置信，恭喜恭喜
I can do a whole monologue album. Incredible. Hey, congratulations.
- 你一飞冲天了，成功了  - 我听候你的差遣，需要我就打个电话
-Yo, blow it up. Boom. MICKEY: I`m your boy. Call me up.
他精通吉他，是个怪才
LUKE: Yeah. Yeah, he`s really good at guitars. He`s a kook.
[ALL LAUGHING AND CHATTERING]
盖伊!等等!
Guy! Wait!
- 你又想怎样，格尔?听你撒更多的谎么?  - 干这行的，哪个不说谎
-What now, Gail? More Iies? -Well, everyone Iies in this business.
这叫圆滑
It`s called spin.
贝芙不会唱歌又怎样
So Bev can`t sing.
杰西卡·辛普森不也出专辑了
That didn`t stop Jessica Simpson.
我给学校董事会打个电话，看看他们作何感想?
Well, we`II see what the school board thinks when I get them a ring, shall we?
你怎么可以这样!教学是我的生命
How dare you? Teaching is my Iife.
别说了，妈妈
Give it up, Mom.
盖伊!
GAIL: Guy!
我的生命之火就要灭了
I will have my nirvana moment.
我会让你相信
[SINGING] I`ll make you believe in me
[COW MOOS]
我可以成为你想要我成为的人
I can be what you want me to be
各位，给点掌声，我可是明星
Oh, come on. Look alive, people. I`m a star.
我们再来一次
Let`s try this again.
我会让你相信
I`ll make you believe--
[CROWD SHOUTING AND BOOING]
噢，不要!你们想要砸死我吗?
Oh, no. You want a piece of me?
嘿，看这里
Hey. CIear.
[YELLS]
今晚跑遍这座城市
[SINGING] Run this town tonight
我的早饭呢?不好意思，忘词了
Where`s breakfast--? Sorry.
[LAUGHS]
我迷失在这个世界，我头脑发懵
I`m lost in a world That rattles my brain
我可以整理好自己的生活，清除你制造的混乱
I`m cleaning up my life From the mess you made, oh, oh
- 凯蒂，你怎么裹了一条地毯?  - 欢迎来我家
-Katie, are you wearing a doormat? -Welcome.
谢谢，现在把裤子给我
Thanks. Now the pants.
之后它会带你去你意料不到的地方
And then it would just take you somewhere that you never expected you would go.
你想听窈窕淑女的独白吗?
[IN ENGLISH ACCENT] You wanna hear the monologue from My Fair Lady?
老兄
Oy, mate, oy.
我爱死我的生活了
I Iove my Iife.
- 等你电话噢  - 你好?
[MOUTHS] Call me. -Hello?
[CROWD CHEERING]
你们喜欢吗?喜欢吧
LUKE: Yeah. You like it? You like it? Yeah.